Spotting Errors
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['We discussed about the problem so thoroughly', 'on the eve of the examination', 'that I found it very easy to work it out', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['An Indian ship', 'laden with merchandise', 'got drowned in the Pacific Ocean.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I could not put up in a hotel', 'because the boarding and lodging charges', 'were exorbitant.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The Indian radio', 'which was previously controlled by the British rulers', 'is free now from the narrow vested interests.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If I had known', 'this yesterday', 'I will have helped him.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A lot of travel delay is caused', 'due to the inefficiency and lack of good management', 'on behalf of the railways.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['One of the members', 'expressed doubt if', 'the Minister was an atheist.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I have got', 'my M.Sc. degree', 'in 1988.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Having received your letter', 'this morning, we are writing', 'to thank you for the same.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If you lend him a book', 'he will lend it to some one else', 'and never you will get it back.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['According to the Bible', 'it is meek and humble', 'who shall inherit the earth.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Do the roses in your garden smell', 'more sweetly', 'than those in ours?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Block of Residential flats', 'are coming up', 'near our house.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['You can get', 'all the information that you want', 'in this book.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The students were', 'awaiting for', 'the arrival of the chief guest.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Sixty miles', 'are', 'a good distance.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['They have been', 'very close friends', 'until they quarrelled.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['When the dentist came in', 'my tooth was stopped aching', 'out of fear that I might lose my tooth.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is the duty of every citizen to do his utmost', 'to defend the hardly-won', 'freedom of the country.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['No sooner did I open the door', 'when the rain, heavy and stormy, rushed in', 'making us shiver from head to foot', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If a man diligently seeks to come into the contact', 'with the best that has been thought and said in this world', 'he will become simple and unselfish.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['You must', 'remember me', 'to post this letter.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I shall certainly', 'write you', 'when I shall reach NewDelhi.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['On the busy Ring Road', 'we witnessed a collusion', 'between a truck and an auto.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Mr.Praful Patel', 'is not attending his office', 'for the last month.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ["He couldn't but help", 'shedding tears at the plight of the villagers', 'rendered homeless by a devastating cyclone.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He will certainly help you', 'if you will ask him', 'in a pleasant manner.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The brand propositon now therefore had to be that Keokarpin Antiseptic Cream is more effective', 'because it penetrates deepdown (beinglight and non-sticky) and works from within', '(because of its ayurvedic ingredients) to keep skin blemish, free and helps cope with cuts nicks, burns and nappy rash.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Will you please buy', 'some jaggery for me', 'if you go to the market?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Most of the members at the meeting felt', 'that the group appointed for investigating the case', 'were not competent to do the job efficiently.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['In these days of inflation,', "a ten rupee's note will not buy you", 'even an ordinary meal.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He persisted', 'to do it', 'in spite of my advice', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The long-awaited moment at last came,', 'and we set out for the station', 'as merry a band of children as I have ever seen before or since.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Our conception of', 'what should a science of mental life be', "has changed considerably since James' time.", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is not coming tomorrow', 'as he is having a pain in the chest', 'and has to see a doctor.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Many times the news has been published', 'in the papers that the end of the world will be certain', 'if a nuclear war breaks out.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The reason Ram', 'is absent from his duty', 'is because he is unwell.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Azharuddin is one of the finest batsmen', 'that India have produced', 'over the decades.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The thief broke in the', 'house at the', 'dead of night', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['May I', 'know who you want', 'to see please', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He said that he', 'will mind if', 'I refused his offer.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ["Arun's parents died when he was young and", 'he looked after his aunt', 'who had no children.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Though child marriage', 'has been banned.', 'the custom still prevailed among some groups in India.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['My papa is', 'in bad mood', 'today', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The warden', 'forbade the student', 'from leaving the hostel.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['In spite of several reminders,', 'he did not so far send', 'any reply to me, letters.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['As much as I admire him for his sterling qualities.', 'I cannot excuse him for', 'being unfair to his friends.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Please try to understand', 'that the dispute on this issue is between my brother and myself,', 'and concerns nobody else.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['All the furnitures have been', 'sent to the new house', 'located in a village.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It does not matter how you do it;', 'what I want is that', 'you should finish the work within a month.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Though senior in age,', 'his father is junior than', 'my father in service.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['While walking slowly in the park', 'on a quiet summer afternoon', 'a mad dog suddenly attacked him from behind', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Everyone visiting the house asked the young girl', 'how could she kill the wolf', 'single handed and without a weapon.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Many health-conscious people', 'prefer margarine', 'than butter.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The retiring principal asked his old pupils', 'to take the interest in the school', 'after he has retired.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['At present juncture', 'however, the supercomputer', 'would be a costly toy.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The crew were on board,', 'and they soon busied themselves', 'in preparing to meet the storm.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Troy was taken by Greeks', 'this formed the basis of a story', 'which has become famous.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I am much pleased', 'to know that', 'you have topped the list.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He has not been attending', 'English classes', 'since one month', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is time', 'we should accept all our people as equals', 'and as partners in the task of building a strong and united nation.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Twice twelve', 'makes', 'twenty-four', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Regretfully, profits earned by your company', 'fell by 20 per cent last year', 'despite higher sales.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['In a report issued by Indian Statistical Institute,', 'the Iron and Steel Industry is investing more than any other', 'Indian industry in fighting pollution.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is going everyday', 'for a morning walk', 'with his friends and neighbours', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['My father goes', 'to the office', 'five day week.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If she will be promoted', 'she will get', 'a higher salary.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If I were him,', 'I would have taught', 'those cheats a lesson.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Looking back, I find that among the many impressions ofthe people of India,', 'absorbed while I lived among them,', 'are their reverence for great men and women.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If you work hard,', 'you will get good grades', 'in examinations.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He managed to make sense of the book', 'even though it was the first time', 'he read anything on the subject.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She reluctantly said that', 'if nobody else was doing it', 'she will do it.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I fail to understand', 'why he replied in negative', 'when the proposal was in his favour.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I have', 'an appointment', "on the 9th September on five o'clock", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['They', 'enjoyed thoroughly', 'at the party.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The method suggested in the lecture', 'enables a student to learn more quickly', 'and to have remembered for a longer period of time.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['My friend asked me', 'if I can lend him my Parker pen', 'for a few days.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The test will not need', 'more than one and half hour', 'to finish.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The school is', 'within hundred yards', 'from the church.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['His father died of cholera', 'but his mother also,', 'though very weak, is out of danger.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The police broke upon the robbers', 'when they were in the lonely place', 'to divide their booty.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Since it was his first election campaign, the candidate was confused;', 'none could clearly understand', 'either the principles he stood for or the benefits he promised.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Jayesh is getting', 'fatter because he', 'does not take exercise at all', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He loved', 'none but', "his neighbour's daughter.", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The criminal was', 'caught, convicted the hung', 'in a short period of time.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I am thinking of', 'to go to Agra', "for my cousin's marriage.", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['In management, as you rise higher,', "the problems you face becomemore and more unstructured and you can't just fall back on", 'the tools you had been', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Neeraj said', 'that he would rather fail than copying', 'in the examination', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I had hoped to have met him yesterday', 'to discuss the matter with him', 'but he was not in his house, and so I could not meet him.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['You will come', 'to my party tomorrow,', "isn't it?", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I wonder', 'how am I', 'to do it', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is not to blame', 'for what has happened', 'for he is in no way connected with it.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Had you not', 'reached in time', 'he would have lost allour belongings.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The man told to her', 'that he had not brought his dog', 'out for a walk as he was afraid that it would rain.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If I am you', 'I would have seen to it', 'that I won the prize.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is unfortunate that', 'many youngsters get', 'addicted to gamble.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ["Kamala's fountain-pen", 'is as expensive', 'as Shyama.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['When we consider all the factors, which are many,', 'the number of school dropouts', 'are quite disturbing.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She has never', 'approve of him', 'working as a clerk.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['At the station,', "I'll hire a coolie", 'to carry my baggages', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The number of marks carried by each question', 'are indicated', 'at the end of the question', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['There is no question', 'of my failing', 'in the examination.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She is', 'no longer popular as she has', 'a friends', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is necessary', 'that everybody', 'must have a house.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Students should not take part', 'in party politics and political demonstrations', 'as they interfere in serious study', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['To facilitate exports and improve sales in the domestic market', 'some of the improvised fabrics and garments fabricated out from them', 'are displayed in the main pavilion.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Both of you two', 'can come with me', 'to the play tonight', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['No sooner did the sun rise', 'when we took a hasty breakfast', 'and resumed the journey.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The charges in this hospital', 'are less than', 'the hospital near my house.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The brakes and steering failed', 'and the bus ran down the hill', 'without anyone being able control it.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The tall three girls', 'had left', 'the day before.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['When he was asked what is wrong with him.', 'he said that he was not well.', 'and asked for leave of absence for one day.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Wherever they go', 'Indians easily adapt to', 'local circumstances.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Remember that you are part of', 'the team and your success depends on the support', 'you are able to give and get from your other team members.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is an established fact that the transcendental American poets and philosophers.', 'who lived in the latter half of the nineteenth century.', 'were more influenced by Indian philosophy, in particular by Upanishadic Philosophy.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['That house', 'is costing me', 'ten thousand rupees', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Firstly you should', 'think over the meaning of the words', 'and then use them.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is true', 'that God helps those', 'who helps themselves.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Happily, zoos were', 'unwilling to cooperate', 'in a scheme that was potentially harmful to animal welfare', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Neither he', 'nor his father is interested', 'in joining the party.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['With little patience', 'you will be able to', 'cross this hurdle', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She was told', 'to give the award to whosoever', 'she thought has done the most for the downtrodden.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['At the end of the year', 'every student who had done adequate work', 'was automatically promoted.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The reason why', 'he was rejected', 'was because he was too young.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Since we are friends', 'there should be no secret', 'between you and I.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Since the attachment of airconditioned sleeping cars to all important trains,', 'travelling became very pleasant,', 'especially during the summer season.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If I will have the time', 'I shall try and make it', 'to the zoo this afternoon.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['We are four brothers and sisters living in this house', 'but neither of us is', 'satisfied with it.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A leading textile manufacturer, one of the fastest growing in the industry.', 'is looking for a marketing manager', 'to look up the marketing network of the company', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Not one of the hundreds', 'of striking workers.', 'were allowed to go near the factory.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The single biggest gainer in this process', "was ITC's Gold Flake Kings sales are estimated", 'to have moved up from 50 million to 200 million sticks per month during 1987 and last year.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['They left', 'their luggages', 'at the railway station.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Salim and Antony are such good friends', "that one won't go to the pictures.", 'without his coming too.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She is', 'five years', 'senior than me.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The President had hardly spoken', 'a few words', 'when the microphone stopped functioning.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ["Locke's treatises on government toleration and education", 'show a mind fully awake in', 'the possibilities of social reconstruction.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['You will get', 'all the information', 'if you read this booklet carefully.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['None of the students attending your class', 'answered your questions', 'did they?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['An animal', 'can be just as unhappy in a vast area', 'or in a small one', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is working in', 'a bank in New Delhi', 'for the past several months.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The scientist must follow', 'his hunches and his data', 'wherever it may lead.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Each one of the boys', 'have paid', 'the tuition-fee.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A large scale exchange of nuclear weapons', 'will produce unprecedented amounts of radiation', 'that can penetrate into the biological tissue.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Had I', 'known it earlier', 'I would contact you.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He asked me', 'why did I call', 'him a rogue.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Were you', 'given a choice', 'or you had to do it?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The person which was', 'recommended for the position', 'did not fulfil the prescribed qualifications.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['What does Professor Dhavan', 'spend so many hours', 'in the laboratory?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The presumption that the average investor does not understand', 'or take interest in the affairs of the company', 'is not correct.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Shanghai is', 'bigger than any city', 'of the world', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Sheela has scored a first class', 'in her final exams,', "isn't it?", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['At the moment the house', 'was burgled the family', 'attended a night party in the neighbourhood.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Scarcely had', 'I arrived than', 'the train left.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Though he stoutly persisted in denying his involvement in the case,', 'the facts made it very clear', 'that he had hand in the cruel murder of his wife.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['One of my favourite actor', 'is acting', 'in this play also.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Emphasis on equality of life ensures', 'for the health and happiness', 'of every individual.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['There was very heavy rain last night,', 'and the rivers have overflown their banks', 'causing severe hardship to the people living by them.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Every motorist knows', 'road signs---whether symbols or colour codes--- have an immediacy', 'that neither the spoken nor the written word can match.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Supposing if', 'there is no bus.', 'how will you get there?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Because of the emergency help', 'that the patient received', 'he would have died', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He was in such hurry', "that he didn't", 'wait for me', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Will you be', 'at Board meeting', 'on next Wednesday?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Do you know', 'to play', 'the guitar?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Few scientists changed', "people's ideas as much as", 'Darwin with his Theory of Evolution.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The course provide', 'not only theoretical inputs', 'but also practical training', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['After the humiliating exposure', 'he hanged his head', 'in shame.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ["The eminent speaker's speech", 'was broadcasted over', 'all the major radio-stations.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The meeting adjourned abruptly', 'by the Chairman after', 'about three hours of deliberation.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The company has put up an advertisement', 'in newspapers', 'all over the country.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Will you lend me', 'little money', 'to tide over this crisis.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He gave them no money', 'nor did help them', 'in any way.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The Sharmas', 'are living in this colony', 'for the last eight years.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['My wife has got', 'a new job', 'a month ago.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The ability to plan,', 'organise and coordinate work is all fundamental', 'to working within deadline.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A group of friends', 'want to visit', 'the new plant as early as possible.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['After leaving his office', 'he went directly', 'to a restaurant.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He was in a hurry', 'because he had an appointment', "with the company's director.", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A body of volunteers', 'have been organised', 'to spread the message of the saint.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['When I get a cold', 'it takes me weeks', 'to shake it off.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Another reason for pharmaceutical companies beefing up their', 'OTC (Over the Country) divisions is that prescription drugs with proven safety records which have been reached', 'the end of the their patent protection periodare', 'allowed to be sold without a prescription. No error'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['There is still', 'little tea', 'left in the cup.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He says that', 'his car does', 'eight kilometers in a litre', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['After opening the door', 'we entered into the room', 'next to the kitchen', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Can I lend', 'your pencil', 'for a minute, please?', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Last month we celebrated', 'the wedding of our sister for whom', 'we have been looking for a suitable alliance for three years.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['In an English paper', 'examiners should give as much weightage to language', 'as they give to contents.', 'No error'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I am hearing', 'a lot about', 'the problem of AIDS these days.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Unless you stop to make noise at once', 'I will have no option but to', 'bring the matter to the attention of the police.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is generally', 'more hungry', 'than she is .', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Since India has gained Independence', '49 years ago.', 'much progress has been made in almost every field.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He ensured his bank manager', 'that he would soon', 'repay the loan.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A free press is not a privilege', 'but the organic necessity', 'in a free society.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He explained the matter', 'at great length', 'but I was not the wiser', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He will end up his work', 'in the city', 'by the end of the year.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Even though the shirt is rather expensive', 'but I wish to', 'purchase it with my own money.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He enquired me', 'why I had not seen him the previous day', 'as I had promised to do.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I was there', 'many a time', 'in the past.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['All the four sons', 'of the old man', 'quarrelled between themselves.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He wanted to work all night', 'but we saw that he was completely worn out', 'and so we persuaded him to stop.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Mr.Smith was accused for murder', 'but the court found him not guilty', 'and acquitted him.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She sang', 'very well', "isn't it?", 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I am sure that all my monthly expenses', 'would exceed the income', 'If I do not economic', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Whenever you go to a temple', 'you must put off', 'your shoes at the entrance.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Having read a number of stories', 'about space travel', 'his dream now is about to visit the moon', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The party chief made it a point to state that', 'the Prime Minister and the Union Home Minister should also come.', 'and they see what his party men had seen.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is easy to see that', "a lawyer's demeanour in court", 'may be prejudicial against the interests of his client.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is wiring', 'for the', 'last four hours', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['She walked in', 'the room where the murder', 'had taken place.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Were he', 'to see you,', 'he would have been surprised.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I could not convince them', 'because they persisted to suggest', 'that I was lying.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['If you listen with', 'the question carefully', 'you will be able to answer them easily', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is difficult', 'for anyone', 'to past time thus.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['The customer handed over', 'a hundred-rupees note', 'to the shopkeeper.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Myself and Gopal', 'will take care of', 'the function on sunday.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['It is the newspaper', 'that exposes us to the widest range', 'of human experiences and behaviour.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Read each sentence to find out whether there is any grammatical error in it. The error, if any will be in one part of the sentence. The letter of that part is the answer. If there is no error, the answer is 'D'. (Ignore the errors of punctuation, if any).
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['A small baby breathes about', '45 times per minute while', 'a child of about six years breathes about 25 times per minute.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['I have read', 'too many books', 'by R . K . Narayan.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He was sure', 'that he should', 'win the Prize.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He is', 'too intelligent', 'to make a mistake.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['He fell from a running train', 'and would have died', 'if the villagers did not get him admitted in the nearby hospital immediately.', 'No error.'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Synonyms
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'CORPULENT', 'options': ['Lean', 'Gaunt', 'Emaciated', 'Obese'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'BRIEF', 'options': ['Limited', 'Small', 'Little', 'Short'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'EMBEZZLE', 'options': ['Misappropriate', 'Balance', 'Remunerate', 'Clear'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'VENT', 'options': ['Opening', 'Stodge', 'End', 'Past tense of go'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'AUGUST', 'options': ['Common', 'Ridiculous', 'Dignified', 'Petty'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'CANNY', 'options': ['Obstinate', 'Handsome', 'Clever', 'Stout'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ALERT', 'options': ['Energetic', 'Observant', 'Intelligent', 'Watchful'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'WARRIOR', 'options': ['Soldier', 'Sailor', 'Pirate', 'Spy'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'DISTANT', 'options': ['Far', 'Removed', 'Reserved', 'Separate'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ADVERSITY', 'options': ['Failure', 'Helplessness', 'Misfortune', 'Crisis'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'FAKE', 'options': ['Original', 'Imitation', 'Trustworthy', 'Loyal'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'INDICT', 'options': ['Condemn', 'Reprimand', 'Accuse', 'Allege'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'STRINGENT', 'options': ['Dry', 'Strained', 'Rigorous', 'Shrill'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'LAMENT', 'options': ['Complain', 'Comment', 'Condone', 'Console'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'HESITATED', 'options': ['Stopped', 'Paused', 'Slowed', 'Postponed'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'RESCUE', 'options': ['Command', 'Help', 'Defence', 'Safety'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ATTEMPT', 'options': ['Serve', 'Explore', 'Try', 'Explain'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FORAY', 'options': ['Maraud', 'Contest', 'Ranger', 'Intuition'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'RECKLESS', 'options': ['Courageous', 'Rash', 'Bold', 'Daring'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'CONSEQUENCES', 'options': ['Results', 'Conclusions', 'Difficulties', 'Applications'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'IMPROVEMENT', 'options': ['Advancement', 'Betterment', 'Promotion', 'Preference'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'INEBRIATE', 'options': ['Dreamy', 'Stupefied', 'Unsteady', 'Drunken'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'STERILE', 'options': ['Barren', 'Arid', 'Childless', 'Dry'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ABJECT', 'options': ['Challenge', 'Miserable', 'Deny', 'Disobey'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'MOVING', 'options': ['Taking', 'Toying', 'Shifting', 'Turning'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'IRONIC', 'options': ['Inflexible', 'Bitter', 'Good-natured', 'Disguisedly sarcastic'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'TIMID', 'options': ['Fast', 'Slow', 'Medium', 'Shy'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'EXTRICATE', 'options': ['Pull', 'Free', 'Tie', 'Complicate'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'NEUTRAL', 'options': ['Unbiased', 'Non-aligned', 'Undecided', 'Indifferent'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'SHALLOW', 'options': ['Artificial', 'Superficial', 'Foolish', 'Worthless'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'DIVERSION', 'options': ['Amusement', 'Distortion', 'Deviation', 'Bylane'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'INSOLVENT', 'options': ['Poor', 'Bankrupt', 'Penniless', 'Broke'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'INEXPLICABLE', 'options': ['Confusing', 'Unaccountable', 'Chaotic', 'Unconnected'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'FEEBLE', 'options': ['Weak', 'Vain', 'Arrogant', 'Sick'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'TRANSIENT', 'options': ['Transparent', 'Fleeting', 'Feeble', 'Fanciful'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'BARE', 'options': ['Uncovered', 'Tolerate', 'Clear', 'Neat'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'REPEAL', 'options': ['Sanction', 'Perpetuate', 'Pass', 'Cancel'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'SALACITY', 'options': ['Bliss', 'Depression', 'Indecency', 'Recession'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ECSTATIC', 'options': ['Animated', 'Bewildered', 'Enraptured', 'Illful'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ADMONISH', 'options': ['Punish', 'Curse', 'Dismiss', 'Reprimand'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'DILIGENT', 'options': ['Progressive', 'Brilliant', 'Inventive', 'Hard-working'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'PIOUS', 'options': ['Pure', 'Pretentious', 'Clean', 'Devout'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'BROWSE', 'options': ['Heal', 'Deceive', 'Examine', 'Strike'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'INFREQUENT', 'options': ['Never', 'Usual', 'Rare', 'Sometimes'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'RESTRAINT', 'options': ['Hindrance', 'Repression', 'Obstacle', 'Restriction'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'DEIFY', 'options': ['Flatter', 'Challenge', 'Worship', 'Face'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'HARBINGER', 'options': ['Messenger', 'Steward', 'Forerunner', 'Pilot'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'VENUE', 'options': ['Place', 'Agenda', 'Time', 'Duration'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'CANDID', 'options': ['Apparent', 'Explicit', 'Frank', 'Bright'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'MELD', 'options': ['To soothe', 'Merge', 'Purchase', 'Glisten'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'LYNCH', 'options': ['Hang', 'Madden', 'Kill', 'Shoot'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'TORTURE', 'options': ['Torment', 'Chastisement', 'Harassment', 'Terror'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ABUNDANT', 'options': ['Ripe', 'Cheap', 'Plenty', 'Absent'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ENTIRE', 'options': ['Part', 'Quarter', 'Whole', 'Half'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'DESTITUTION', 'options': ['Humility', 'Moderation', 'Poverty', 'Beggary'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'WRETCHED', 'options': ['Poor', 'Foolish', 'Insane', 'Strained'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'INTIMIDATE', 'options': ['To hint', 'Frighten', 'Bluff', 'Harass'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'CANTANKEROUS', 'options': ['Quarrelsome', 'Rash', 'Disrespectful', 'Noisy'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'RANT', 'options': ['Praise inordinately', 'Formalise', 'To preach noisily', 'Treat with screen'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ZANY', 'options': ['Clown', 'Pet', 'Thief', 'Magician'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'TACITURNITY', 'options': ['Dumbness', 'Changeablemess', 'Hesitation', 'Reserve'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'MASSACRE', 'options': ['Murder', 'Stab', 'Assassinate', 'Slaughter'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'KEN', 'options': ['Ignorance', 'Witness', 'Trial', 'Knowledge'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'WARY', 'options': ['Sad', 'vigilant', 'Distorted', 'Tired'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'RABBLE', 'options': ['Mob', 'Noise', 'Roar', 'Rubbish'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'MAYHEM', 'options': ['Jubilation', 'Havoc', 'Excitement', 'Defeat'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'PONDER', 'options': ['Think', 'Evaluate', 'Anticipate', 'Increase'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'CONNOISSEUR', 'options': ['Ignorant', 'Lover of art', 'Interpreter', 'Delinquent'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'SHIVER', 'options': ['Feel', 'Rock', 'Tremble', 'Move'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'PRESTIGE', 'options': ['Influence', 'Quality', 'Name', 'Wealth'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'STRINGENT', 'options': ['Tense', 'Stringly', 'Strict', 'Causing to Shrink'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'INSOMNIA', 'options': ['Lethargy', 'Sleeplessness', 'Drunkenness', 'Unconsciousness'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'LAUD', 'options': ['Lord', 'Eulogy', 'Praise', 'Extolled'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'REPERCUSSION', 'options': ['Clever reply', 'Recollection', 'Remuneration', 'Reaction'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'IMPROMPTU', 'options': ['Offhand', 'Unimportant', 'Unreal', 'Effective'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'FRUGALITY', 'options': ['Foolishness', 'Extremity', 'Enthusiasm', 'Economy'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'CORRESPONDENCE', 'options': ['Agreements', 'Contracts', 'Documents', 'Letters'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'ASCEND', 'options': ['Leap', 'Grow', 'Deviate', 'Mount'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'FURORE', 'options': ['Excitement', 'Worry', 'Flux', 'Anteroom'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'SYNOPSIS', 'options': ['Index', 'Mixture', 'Summary', 'Puzzles'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'TURN UP', 'options': ['Land up', 'Show up', 'Crop up', 'Come up'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'VIGOUR', 'options': ['Strength', 'Boldness', 'Warmth', 'Enthusism'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'GARNISH', 'options': ['Paint', 'Garner', 'Adorn', 'Abuse'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'MENDACIOUS', 'options': ['Full of Confidence', 'False', 'Encouraging', 'Provocative'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'GARRULITY', 'options': ['Credulity', 'Senility', 'Loquaciousness', 'Speciousness'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'MOROSE', 'options': ['Annoyed', 'Gloomy', 'Moody', 'Displeased'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'VORACIOUS', 'options': ['Truthful', 'Gluttonous', 'Funny', 'Venturous'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'AWAKENED', 'options': ['Enlightened', 'Realised', 'Shook', 'Waken'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'GRATIFY', 'options': ['Appreciate', 'Frank', 'Indulge', 'Pacify'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'PRECARIOUS', 'options': ['Cautious', 'Critical', 'Perilous', 'Brittle'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'INFAMY', 'options': ['Dishonour', 'Glory', 'Integrity', 'Reputation'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'MASTERLY', 'options': ['Crafty', 'Skilful', 'Meaningful', 'Cruel'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'SCINTILLATING', 'options': ['Smouldering', 'Glittering', 'Touching', 'Warming'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'TEPID', 'options': ['Hot', 'Warm', 'Cold', 'Boiling'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'VORACIOUS', 'options': ['Wild', 'Greedy', 'Angry', 'Quick'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'UNITE', 'options': ['Unfold', 'Unchain', 'Combine', 'Unhinge'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'COMBAT', 'options': ['Conflict', 'Quarrel', 'Feud', 'Fight'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'REFECTORY', 'options': ['Restaurant', 'Parlour', 'Living Room', 'Dining Room'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'UNCOUTH', 'options': ['Ungraceful', 'Rough', 'Slovenly', 'Dirty'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ERROR', 'options': ['Misadventure', 'Misgiving', 'Ambiguity', 'Blunder'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following the questions choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.
[{'question': 'COMMENSURATE', 'options': ['Measurable', 'Proportionate', 'Begining', 'Appropriate'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'DEBACLE', 'options': ['Collapse', 'Decline', 'Defeat', 'Disgrace'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'GERMANE', 'options': ['Responsible', 'Logical', 'Possible', 'Relevant'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'DISTINCTION', 'options': ['Diffusion', 'Disagreement', 'Different', 'Degree'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Antonyms
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'ENORMOUS', 'options': ['Soft', 'Average', 'Tiny', 'Weak'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'COMMISSIONED', 'options': ['Started', 'Closed', 'Finished', 'Terminated'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'ARTIFICIAL', 'options': ['Red', 'Natural', 'Truthful', 'Solid'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'EXODUS', 'options': ['Influx', 'Home-coming', 'Return', 'Restoration'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'RELINQUISH', 'options': ['Abdicate', 'Renounce', 'Possess', 'Deny'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'EXPAND', 'options': ['Convert', 'Condense', 'Congest', 'Conclude'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'MORTAL', 'options': ['Divine', 'Immortal', 'Spiritual', 'Eternal'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'QUIESCENT', 'options': ['ACTIVE', 'Dormant', 'Weak', 'Unconcerned'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'OBEYING', 'options': ['Ordering', 'Following', 'Refusing', 'Contradicting'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'FRAUDULENT', 'options': ['Candid', 'Direct', 'Forthright', 'Genuine'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'FLAGITIOUS', 'options': ['Innocent', 'Vapid', 'Ignorant', 'Frivolous'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'BELITTLE', 'options': ['Criticize', 'Flatter', 'Exaggerate', 'Adore'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'STARTLED', 'options': ['Amused', 'Relaxed', 'Endless', 'Astonished'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'BUSY', 'options': ['Occupied', 'Engrossed', 'Relaxed', 'Engaged'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FRESH', 'options': ['Faulty', 'Sluggish', 'Disgraceful', 'Stale'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'CULPABLE', 'options': ['Defendable', 'Blameless', 'Careless', 'Irresponsible'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'EVASIVE', 'options': ['Free', 'Honest', 'Liberal', 'Frank'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'GREGARIOUS', 'options': ['Antisocial', 'Glorious', 'Horrendous', 'Similar'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'AWARE', 'options': ['Uncertain', 'Ignorant', 'Sure', 'Doubtful'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'HIRSUTE', 'options': ['Scaly', 'Bald', 'Erudite', 'Quiet'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'SHRINK', 'options': ['Contract', 'Spoil', 'Expand', 'Stretch'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'COMMON', 'options': ['Rare', 'Small', 'Petty', 'Poor'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'COMFORT', 'options': ['Uncomfort', 'Miscomfort', 'Discomfort', 'None Of These'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'DEAR', 'options': ['Priceless', 'Free', 'Worthless', 'Cheap'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'ARROGANT', 'options': ['Humble', 'Cowardly', 'Egotistic', 'Gentlemanly'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'VICTORIOUS', 'options': ['Defeated', 'Annexed', 'Destroyed', 'Vanquished'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'GRACEFUL', 'options': ['Rough', 'Expert', 'Miserable', 'Awkward'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'NADIR', 'options': ['Modernity', 'Zenith', 'Liberty', 'Progress'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'EXTRAVAGANCE', 'options': ['Luxury', 'Poverty', 'Economical', 'Cheapness'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'PERTINENT', 'options': ['Irrational', 'Irregular', 'Insistent', 'Irrelevant'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'OBSCURE', 'options': ['Implicit', 'Obnoxious', 'Explicit', 'Pedantic'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'URBANE', 'options': ['Illiterate', 'Backward', 'Discourteous', 'Orthodox'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'VANITY', 'options': ['Pride', 'Humility', 'Conceit', 'Ostentatious'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'RARELY', 'options': ['Hardly', 'Definately', 'Frequently', 'Periodically'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'MALICIOUS', 'options': ['Kind', 'Boastful', 'Generous', 'Indifferent'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'EPILOGUE', 'options': ['Dialogue', 'Prelude', 'Post script', 'Epigram'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'CAPACIOUS', 'options': ['Limited', 'Caring', 'Foolish', 'Changeable'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'CONDENSE', 'options': ['Expand', 'Distribute', 'Interpret', 'Lengthen'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ADAPTABLE', 'options': ['Adoptable', 'Flexible', 'Yielding', 'Rigid'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'SACROSANCT', 'options': ['Irreligious', 'Unethical', 'Irreverent', 'Unholy'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'INDISCREET', 'options': ['Reliable', 'Honest', 'Prudent', 'Stupid'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FAMILIAR', 'options': ['Unpleasant', 'Dangerous', 'Friendly', 'Strange'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'TANGIBLE', 'options': ['Ethereal', 'Concrete', 'Actual', 'Solid'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'LOVE', 'options': ['Villainy', 'Hatred', 'Compulsion', 'Force'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'FAMOUS', 'options': ['Disgraced', 'Unknown', 'Evil', 'Popular'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'ABSOLUTE', 'options': ['Deficient', 'Faulty', 'Limited', 'Scarce'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FRUGAL', 'options': ['Copious', 'Extravagant', 'Generous', 'Ostentatious'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'INSIPID', 'options': ['Tasty', 'Stupid', 'Discreet', 'Feast'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ABLE', 'options': ['Disable', 'Inable', 'Unable', 'Misable'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'HOSTILITY', 'options': ['Courtesy', 'Hospitality', 'Relationship', 'Friendliness'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'CROWDED', 'options': ['Busy', 'Congested', 'Quiet', 'Deserted'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'COMIC', 'options': ['Emotional', 'Tragic', 'Fearful', 'Painful'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'HAPLESS', 'options': ['Cheerful', 'Consistent', 'Fortunate', 'Shapely'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FLIMSY', 'options': ['Frail', 'Filthy', 'Firm', 'Flippant'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'EQUANIMITY', 'options': ['Resentment', 'Dubiousness', 'Duplicity', 'Excitement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'ADDITION', 'options': ['Division', 'Enumeration', 'Subtraction', 'Multiplication'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'ZENITH', 'options': ['Acme', 'Top', 'Nadir', 'Pinnacle'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'DOUBTFUL', 'options': ['Famous', 'Certain', 'Fixed', 'Important'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'PERENNIAL', 'options': ['Frequent', 'Regular', 'Lasting', 'Rare'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'BENIGN', 'options': ['Malevolent', 'Soft', 'Friendly', 'Unwise'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'HINDRANCE', 'options': ['Aid', 'Persuasion', 'Cooperation', 'Agreement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'EXTRICATE', 'options': ['Manifest', 'Palpable', 'Release', 'Entangle'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'REPRESS', 'options': ['Inhibit', 'Liberate', 'Curb', 'Quell'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ACQUITTED', 'options': ['Freed', 'Burdened', 'Convicted', 'Entrusted'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'PROVOCATION', 'options': ['Vocation', 'Pacification', 'Peace', 'Destruction'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'SUBSERVIENT', 'options': ['Aggressive', 'Straightforward', 'Dignified', 'Supercilious'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'LEND', 'options': ['Borrow', 'Cheat', 'Pawn', 'Hire'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'FAINT-HEARTED', 'options': ['Warm-hearted', 'Full-blooded', 'Hot-blooded', 'Stout-hearted'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'REMISS', 'options': ['Forgetful', 'Watchful', 'Dutiful', 'Harmful'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'TRANSPARENT', 'options': ['Semi-transparent', 'Muddy', 'Opaque', 'Dark'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'HONORARY', 'options': ['Dishonorable', 'Reputed', 'Paid', 'Official'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'METICULOUS', 'options': ['Mutual', 'Shaggy', 'Meretricious', 'Slovenly'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'LOQUACIOUS', 'options': ['Reticent', 'Talkative', 'Garrulous', 'Verbose'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'CONFESS', 'options': ['Deny', 'Refuse', 'Contest', 'Contend'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ANNOY', 'options': ['Praise', 'Rejoice', 'Please', 'Reward'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'REPEL', 'options': ['Attend', 'Concentrate', 'Continue', 'Attract'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'SUPPRESS', 'options': ['Encourage', 'Allow', 'Praise', 'Permit'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'NIGGARDLY', 'options': ['Frugal', 'Thrifty', 'Stingy', 'Generous'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'IMPASSE', 'options': ['Resurgence', 'Breakthrough', 'Continuation', 'Combination'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'HAPHAZARD', 'options': ['Fortuitous', 'Indifferent', 'Deliberate', 'Accidental'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'DENSITY', 'options': ['Rarity', 'Intelligence', 'Clarity', 'Brightness'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'ADHERENT', 'options': ['Detractor', 'Enemy', 'Alien', 'Rival'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'BASE', 'options': ['Climax', 'Height', 'Top', 'Roof'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'PATCHY', 'options': ['Attractive', 'Uniform', 'Simple', 'Clear'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ENMITY', 'options': ['Important', 'Unnecessary', 'Friendship', 'Likeness'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'HOLLOW', 'options': ['Filled', 'Solid', 'Strong', 'Substantial'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'VALUABLE', 'options': ['Invaluable', 'Worthless', 'Inferior', 'Lowly'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'GULLIBLE', 'options': ['Incredulous', 'Fickle', 'Easy', 'Stylish'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'INDUSTRIOUS', 'options': ['Indifferent', 'Indolent', 'Casual', 'Passive'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'AUTONOMY', 'options': ['Slavery', 'Subordination', 'Dependence', 'Submissiveness'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'ALIEN', 'options': ['Native', 'Domiciled', 'Natural', 'Resident'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'SYNTHETIC', 'options': ['Affable', 'Natural', 'Plastic', 'Cosmetic'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'BALANCE', 'options': ['Disbalance', 'Misbalance', 'Debalance', 'Imbalance'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'LIABILITY', 'options': ['Property', 'Assets', 'Debt', 'Treasure'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'MOUNTAIN', 'options': ['Plain', 'Plateau', 'Precipice', 'Valley'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'STATIONARY', 'options': ['Active', 'Mobile', 'Rapid', 'Busy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'CONCEDE', 'options': ['Object', 'Refuse', 'Grant', 'Accede'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'VIOLENT', 'options': ['Humble', 'Harmless', 'Gentle', 'Tame'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'VIRTUOUS', 'options': ['Wicked', 'Corrupt', 'Vicious', 'Scandalous'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'GAIN', 'options': ['Loose', 'Fall', 'Lost', 'Lose'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'PRELIMINARY', 'options': ['Final', 'First', 'Secondary', 'Initial'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'DEFIANCE', 'options': ['Anxiety', 'Obedience', 'Suspicion', 'Dismay'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ENCOURAGE', 'options': ['Dampen', 'Disapprove', 'Discourage', 'Warn'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'LUCID', 'options': ['Glory', 'Noisy', 'Obscure', 'Distinct'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'STRINGENT', 'options': ['General', 'Vehement', 'Lenient', 'Magnanimous'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the following questions choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.
[{'question': 'MINOR', 'options': ['Big', 'Major', 'Tall', 'Heavy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'REVEALED', 'options': ['Denied', 'Concealed', 'Ignored', 'Overlooked'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ESSENTIAL', 'options': ['Extra', 'Noughts', 'Minors', 'Trivial'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'HYPOCRITICAL', 'options': ['Gentle', 'Sincere', 'Amiable', 'Dependable'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'FICKLE', 'options': ['Courageous', 'Sincere', 'Steadfast', 'Humble'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Selecting Words
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Fate smiles ...... those who untiringly grapple with stark realities of life.', 'options': ['with', 'over', 'on', 'round'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The miser gazed ...... at the pile of gold coins in front of him.', 'options': ['avidly', 'admiringly', 'thoughtfully', 'earnestly'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Catching the earlier train will give us the ...... to do some shopping.', 'options': ['chance', 'luck', 'possibility', 'occasion'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I saw a ...... of cows in the field.', 'options': ['group', 'herd', 'swarm', 'flock'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The grapes are now ...... enough to be picked.', 'options': ['ready', 'mature', 'ripe', 'advanced'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Success in this examination depends ...... hard work alone.', 'options': ['at', 'over', 'for', 'on'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'My uncle decided to take ...... and my sister to the market.', 'options': ['I', 'mine', 'me', 'myself'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'If you smuggle goods into the country, they may be ...... by the customs authority.', 'options': ['possessed', 'punished', 'confiscated', 'fined'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Man does not live by ...... alone.', 'options': ['food', 'bread', 'meals', 'diet'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Piyush behaves strangely at times and, therefore, nobody gets ...... with him.', 'options': ['about', 'through', 'along', 'up'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Rohan and Rohit are twin brothers, but they do not look ......', 'options': ['unique', 'different', 'likely', 'alike'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'To err is ...... to forgive divine.', 'options': ['beastly', 'human', 'inhuman', 'natural'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The ruling party will have to put its own house ...... order.', 'options': ['in', 'on', 'to', 'into'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '...... of old paintings is a job for experts.', 'options': ['Resurrection', 'Retrieval', 'Restoration', 'Resumption'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'During Diwali the shops are ...... of people.', 'options': ['busy', 'full', 'crowded', 'bubbling'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The paths of glory lead ...... to the grave.', 'options': ['straight', 'but', 'in', 'directly'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The telephone ...... several times before I answered it.', 'options': ['was ringing', 'has rung', 'had rung', 'would ring'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He passed the examination in the first class because he ......', 'options': ['was hard working for it', 'worked hardly for it', 'had worked hard for it', 'was working hard for it'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Jawaharlal spent his childhood ...... Anand Bhawan.', 'options': ['at', 'in', 'on', 'across'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'If negotiations are to prove fruitful, there must not only be sincerity on each side, but there must also be ...... in the sincerity of the other side.', 'options': ['faith', 'belief', 'substance', 'certainty'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'I hate sitting ...... him as he always smells of garlic.', 'options': ['besides', 'along', 'at', 'beside'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Some regions of our country still remain ...... to the average man.', 'options': ['inaccessible', 'impossible', 'impermeable', 'impenetrable'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'It ...... that Prashant will not be selected for the post', 'options': ['feels', 'looks', 'believes', 'seems'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'In Bush, Saddam was up ...... more than his match.', 'options': ['for', 'into', 'against', 'to'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "I haven't seen you ...... a week.", 'options': ['within', 'since', 'for', 'from'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'I listened, but I had no idea what he was ...... about.', 'options': ['saying', 'talking', 'telling', 'discussing'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The car in which the minister was traveling ...... with an accident.', 'options': ['hit', 'drove', 'crashed', 'met'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The non cooperative attitude of the members can only ...... the image of the society.', 'options': ['spoil', 'improve', 'degrade', 'defame'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Sonika is quite intelligent but rather ......', 'options': ['idealistic', 'generous', 'lazy', 'optimistic'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'In a little-publicised deal, Pepsi, Cola has ...... the entire soft drink market in Afghanistan.', 'options': ['occupied', 'conquered', 'swallowed', 'captured'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': "He ...... in wearing the old fashioned coat in spite of his wife's disapproval.", 'options': ['insists', 'persists', 'desists', 'resists'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'She ...... a brief appearance at the end of party.', 'options': ['put on', 'put in', 'put across', 'put up'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Life is to death as pleasure is to ......', 'options': ['poverty', 'suffering', 'anguish', 'pain'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'This, partly, explains how the Mehta family has been able to ...... its lavish lifestyle in recent times, despite the fact that all its assets have been ......', 'options': ['keep, removed', 'afford, attached', 'develop, liquidated', 'keep up, destroyed'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The machine is difficult to build ...... easy to maintain.', 'options': ['but', 'and', 'for', 'if'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'If you work beyond your capacity, you will naturally feel ......', 'options': ['drowsy', 'tired', 'confident', 'giddy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If you persists in telling lies to me I shall sue you ...... slander.', 'options': ['to', 'on', 'for', 'with'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'His father-in-law ...... him up in business.', 'options': ['put', 'made', 'set', 'built'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '...... works of reference are valuable as Encyclopedia, Brittanica.', 'options': ['A few', 'Few', 'The few', 'Fewer'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'This book is quite similar ......', 'options': ['with the "Treasure Island"', 'of that film we saw at school', 'to the one I read last week', 'than a story told by our teacher'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'If our friends are not able to take us in their car, we must make ...... arrangements to go to the airport.', 'options': ['alternative', 'another', 'alternate', 'possible'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A crescendo of metallic thuds arose from the market, where the iron-smiths were ...... the pieces of metals.', 'options': ['flattening', 'striking', 'hammering', 'thrashing'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "I haven't eaten an apple ...... a long while.", 'options': ['from', 'since', 'for', 'until'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The parliament invested the new organisation ...... judicial authority.', 'options': ['by', 'with', 'from', 'through'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Owing to the power cut in the area, factories are being forced to ...... men', 'options': ['throw away', 'send off', 'put off', 'lay off'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Man must ...... to stop pollution.', 'options': ['act', 'perform', 'operate', 'behave'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He was sent to the prison for his ......', 'options': ['sin', 'vice', 'crime', 'guilt'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The answer was written ...... blue ink.', 'options': ['with', 'by', 'in', 'on'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Many ...... decisions were taken at the meeting.', 'options': ['hectic', 'historic', 'historical', 'histrionic'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Those who persist in the endeavor at long last triumph ...... the odds of life.', 'options': ['over', 'on', 'upon', 'about'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'In the modern materialistic society, the only aim of people appears to be ...... money by fair means or foul.', 'options': ['print', 'produce', 'acquire', 'extort'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'What is the ...... for an air letter?', 'options': ['fare', 'value', 'postage', 'stamp'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He became enamored ...... her grace when he first saw her dance.', 'options': ['with', 'of', 'by', 'in'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Rama was so badly injured that he needed ...... care in the hospital.', 'options': ['extensive', 'little', 'deep', 'intensive'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'You cannot devise a method which ...... all possibility of errors.', 'options': ['excludes', 'includes', 'avoids', 'ignores'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Many areas of the city were ...... into darkness for several hours.', 'options': ['spread', 'plunged', 'merged', 'deep'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Find the ...... that accompany these cartoons.', 'options': ['topics', 'titles', 'captions', 'headings'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "I don't really know how to ...... the problem.", 'options': ['tackle', 'cope', 'draw', 'erase'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The English schemed to continue their rule in India by playing off one community ...... the other.', 'options': ['before', 'upon', 'against', 'with'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The passengers were afraid, but the captain ...... them that there was no danger.', 'options': ['promised', 'assured', 'advised', 'counselled'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The family gave father a gold watch on the ...... of his fiftieth birthday.', 'options': ['time', 'event', 'occasion', 'celebration'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The park ...... as far as the river.', 'options': ['extends', 'advances', 'enlarges', 'emerges'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Many of the advances of civilisation have been conceived by young people just on the ...... of adulthood', 'options': ['boundary', 'threshold', 'peak', 'horizon'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Arti pulled a long ...... when she was told that she could not go to Agra.', 'options': ['mouth', 'skirt', 'face', 'hand'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Brothers must live in harmony. They must never fall ......', 'options': ['off', 'out', 'apart', 'away'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'I was astounded at his ...... lack of knowledge about the Continent of Africa.', 'options': ['abundant', 'colossal', 'huge', 'great'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Ayesha always ...... the permission of her father before going for movies.', 'options': ['seeking', 'seeks', 'sought', 'seeker'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He felt no ...... as he plunged the knife into her back.', 'options': ['qualms', 'scruple', 'conscience', 'morals'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "You haven't had your lunch yet, ...... you?", 'options': ['are', "aren't", 'have', "haven't"], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The manner in which bombs exploded in five trains with in a short span of time suggests that it is a part of a ......', 'options': ['game', 'conspiracy', 'villainy', 'sabotage'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Wheat ...... carbohydrates, vitamins, proteins, and dietary fibre in our daily diet.', 'options': ['has', 'gives', 'yields', 'provides'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "The waiter hasn't brought the coffee ...... I've been here an hour already.", 'options': ['till', 'up', 'yet', 'still'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'In our zeal for progress we should not ...... executive with more power.', 'options': ['avoid', 'give', 'enhance', 'arm'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "You've only three months to complete the course, Don't give ...... now.", 'options': ['out', 'away', 'up', 'off'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The traveler slept under the ...... shade of banyan tree.', 'options': ['cold', 'cool', 'cooling', 'dark'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'She has an aversion ...... taking even onion and garlic.', 'options': ['with', 'at', 'against', 'to'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The river overflowed its ...... and flooded the area.', 'options': ['edges', 'fronts', 'limits', 'banks'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '...... The arrival of the police, nobody went near the victim.', 'options': ['Unless', 'Although', 'Even', 'Till'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'When I was a child, I ......to school everyday instead going by cycle.', 'options': ['had walked', 'walked', 'have walked', 'have been walking'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Farida sings very well and ...... does salim.', 'options': ['even', 'too', 'also', 'so'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The old Nature versus ...... debate regarding crime continues even today.', 'options': ['Man', 'Universe', 'Culture', 'Nurture'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The Sun ...... at six this morning.', 'options': ['raised', 'rose', 'arose', 'aroused'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'That rule is applicable ...... every one.', 'options': ['to', 'for', 'about', 'with'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Her parents will never give their ...... to so much an unsuitable match.', 'options': ['acquiescence', 'consent', 'agreement', 'willingness'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He tried to ...... himself against a horde of ruffians.', 'options': ['collect', 'save', 'support', 'defend'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': "According to corporate circles data is pushing through the merger to create financially ...... company in the processed foods business, the group's thrust area for the 1990's", 'options': ['acceptable', 'powerful', 'leading', 'straight'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Indeed, all over the world, more and more people are ...... coffee.', 'options': ['wanting', 'drinking', 'liking', 'partaking'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Like any other country India has its ...... share of superstitions.', 'options': ['proper', 'abundant', 'fair', 'peculiar'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The new education policy provides a useful ...... for the planners to remove illiteracy.', 'options': ['breakup', 'breakthrough', 'breakaway', 'break-in'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'People who ...... on horses usually lose in the end.', 'options': ['gamble', 'play', 'risk', 'place'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'About twenty clerks were made ...... when the banks introduced computers.', 'options': ['dispensable', 'redundant', 'expandable', 'obsolete'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'After the rain the weather ...... and the sun came out.', 'options': ['cleared out', 'cleared up', 'cleared away', 'cleared off'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The building comprises ...... sixty rooms.', 'options': ['of', 'onto', 'by', 'no preposition needed'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Namrata was found to ...... the required qualifications for the job.', 'options': ['contain', 'disclose', 'posses', 'acquire'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Government buildings are ...... on the Republic day.', 'options': ['enlightened', 'lightened', 'illuminated', 'glowed'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'we had ...... wonderful time at the party last night.', 'options': ['such a', 'so', 'such', 'very'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'An employment advertisement should ...... the number of vacancies.', 'options': ['provide', 'specify', 'contain', 'declare'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'When varun left the cocktail party he was as ...... as a judge.', 'options': ['sober', 'drunk', 'brave', 'wise'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The criminal seems to have acted in ...... the three others.', 'options': ['collusion', 'coalition', 'collision', 'cohesion'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Soft minded individuals are ...... to embrace all kinds superstitions.', 'options': ['disposed', 'eager', 'reluctant', 'prone'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The stenographer is very efficient. He is ...... to his firm.', 'options': ['a boon', 'a credit', 'a blessing', 'an asset'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "However, the group's long-term strategy is to ...... on core sector business connected with infrastructure and energy.", 'options': ['breed', 'develop', 'concentrate', 'depend'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The man came in a van to ...... the television set.', 'options': ['mend', 'reform', 'correct', 'alter'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Nobody can ...... me to do anything which I do not want to do.', 'options': ['encourage', 'request', 'oppose', 'compel'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A sanguine outlook is associated with the ......', 'options': ['rationalist', 'socialist', 'philanthropist', 'optimist'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'His conduct is bad, and his honesty is not ...... suspicion.', 'options': ['above', 'beyond', 'under', 'in'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'It is 14 years since i ...... him.', 'options': ['have seen', 'had seen', 'saw', 'see'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It being an ...... issue, it is not correct to introduce questions of morality in to the debate.', 'options': ['moral', 'immoral', 'amoral', 'irrelevant'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Natwarlal ...... them all for a ride by producing false documents.', 'options': ['took', 'cheated', 'kept', 'let'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'True brevity ...... in saying only what needs to be said.', 'options': ['consists', 'depicts', 'portrays', 'resides'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Health is too important to be ......', 'options': ['discarded', 'despised', 'detested', 'neglected'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'In hot weather I like lying in the ...... of a tree.', 'options': ['shade', 'shelter', 'protection', 'shadow'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'It was indeed unreasonable ...... him to leave this job and start business.', 'options': ['in', 'with', 'upon', 'of'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'One major ...... between the Election Commission and the Union Government related to the powers of the former in respect of the deployment of central police forces at places where are elections is held.', 'options': ['irritant', 'conflict', 'pain', 'culprit'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'We shall not to be able to use your ability in court unless we can find someone to ...... to statements.', 'options': ['corroborate', 'avouch', 'verify', 'approve'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'He is too dull ...... this problem.', 'options': ['solving', 'to solving', 'to solve', 'solves'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He is the person who is ...... to blame.', 'options': ['mostly', 'sure', 'most', 'bound'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'We had to pay more taxi fare because the driver brought us by a ...... route.', 'options': ['circular', 'circumscribed', 'longest', 'circuitous'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "He was accused ...... stealing his aunt's necklace.", 'options': ['for', 'with', 'of', 'on'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He knew everything better than anybody else, and it was an affront to his ...... vanity that you should disagree with him.', 'options': ['overstrung', 'overweening', 'overwhelming', 'overwrought'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': "It's very kind of you to ...... to speak at the meeting.", 'options': ['accept', 'agree', 'comply', 'concur'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Pakistan lost a ...... wicket just when they seemed to be doing so well, and that led to their eventual defeat.', 'options': ['critical', 'crucial', 'sensitive', 'providential'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "Sita's heart ...... at the sight of the beautiful diamond necklace.", 'options': ['leapt', 'stopped', 'slowed', 'ran'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He lives near a lovely ...... of countryside.', 'options': ['length', 'piece', 'section', 'stretch'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Ambition is one of those ......which are never satisfied.', 'options': ['ideas', 'fancies', 'passions', 'feeds'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'He is a person of sound character and ...... disposition.', 'options': ['beneficent', 'morous', 'amiable', 'amicable'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "If I take a state roadways bus, I'll get late, ...... ?", 'options': ["isn't it", "won't I", 'will I', 'is it'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'In high school many of us never realised the importance that grammar would ...... in later life.', 'options': ['figure', 'portray', 'play', 'exercise'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'In a changing and ...... unstructured business environment, creativity and innovation are being ...... demanded of executives.', 'options': ['highly, extremely', 'progressively, increasingly', 'increasingly, moderately', 'excessively, rapidly'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'On account of the dearth of grass on the arid plains the cattle became ......', 'options': ['flippant', 'jubilant', 'agitated', 'emaciated'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'A woman came in with a baby who, she said, ...... a safety pin.', 'options': ['was just swallowing', 'swallowed', 'had just swallowed', 'just swallowed'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The Hubble Space Telescope will search for planets around the stars, a key to the ...... extraterrestrial life, and examine interstellar dust and gases out of which stars are born.', 'options': ['perception', 'discovery', 'enquiry', 'quest'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'She ...... Rs 80 out of the bank every Friday.', 'options': ['obtains', 'draws', 'pulls', 'extracts'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The American ...... presented his credentials to the President of India.', 'options': ['adviser', 'ambassador', 'delegate', 'representative'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "Once he has signed the agreement, he won't be able to ......", 'options': ['back up', 'back in', 'back at', 'back out'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'It was difficult to remove my feet as it had got stuck ...... in the mud.', 'options': ['fairly', 'greatly', 'widely', 'firmly'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'He is a very careful person, he never takes side but remains ......', 'options': ['impartial', 'unbiased', 'neutral', 'prejudiced'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'West Bengal ...... plentiful rainfall and is consequently a very green part of the country.', 'options': ['misses', 'receives', 'expects', 'regrets'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'this brand of TV is quite inferior ...... that one.', 'options': ['than', 'to', 'with', 'over'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'It is not what you say that ...... but what you do', 'options': ['matches', 'implies', 'matters', 'moves'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': "'Please' and 'Thank you' are the little courtesies by which we keep the ...... of life oiled and running smoothly.", 'options': ['path', 'machine', 'garden', 'river'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'I put ...... the light and slept.', 'options': ['up', 'down', 'in', 'out'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '...... all intents and purposes, the manager is the master of the firm.', 'options': ['in', 'upon', 'with', 'to'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The pilot had been warned about the storm, before he ......', 'options': ['took away', 'took up', 'took over', 'took off'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Hardly had he arrived ...... it started raining.', 'options': ['before', 'when', 'than', 'after'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'I ...... a car to be absolutely necessary these days.', 'options': ['consider', 'regard', 'think', 'agree'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Besides other provisions, that shopkeeper deals ...... cosmetics.', 'options': ['with', 'in', 'at', 'for'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "Leave a two inch ...... on each page for the teacher's remarks.", 'options': ['border', 'margin', 'blank', 'gap'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The team was well trained and strong, but somehow their ...... was low.', 'options': ['feeling', 'moral', 'consciousness', 'morale'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The lovers were meeting each other secretly, but their ...... affair was soon known to everyone.', 'options': ['clandestine', 'covert', 'unknown', 'candid'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The king ...... the rebel.', 'options': ['excused', 'forgave', 'pardoned', 'none of these'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'I shall call ...... you tomorrow.', 'options': ['at', 'on', 'with', 'by'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'She ...... from the crowd because of her height and flaming red hair.', 'options': ['stood out', 'stood off', 'stood up', 'stood by'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'In a large cities people are cut ...... from nature.', 'options': ['away', 'off', 'out', 'down'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The more your action and thought are allied and ...... the happier you grow.', 'options': ['diverget', 'unravelled', 'integrated', 'invincible'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'We had a ...... of warm weather in February.', 'options': ['time', 'spell', 'length', 'phase'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Physically we are now all neighbors, but psychologically. we are ...... to each other.', 'options': ['primitives', 'complimentary', 'strangers', 'cowards'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'When their examinations are over, the children gleefully ...... the books they had been reading.', 'options': ['shelve', 'sidetrack', 'overthrew', 'abandon'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Chintu is ...... small to start playing cricket now.', 'options': ['very', 'much', 'too', 'more'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The thief ...... all the money.', 'options': ['made up', 'made off with', 'mode do with', 'made good'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The luggage was ...... heavy for him to lift', 'options': ['much', 'as', 'so', 'too'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "Walking at 3'o clock, I heard the ...... of thunder.", 'options': ['crackle', 'rumble', 'ripple', 'clank'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A stone that goes on rolling ...... no moss.', 'options': ['collects', 'gets', 'gathers', 'accumulates'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The earth is at present in great danger of becoming uninhabitable because of ...... environmental pollution which is going on at an incredible rapid pace.', 'options': ['gigantic', 'inhuman', 'stupendous', 'colossal'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Moreover, a fact finding mission ...... by BSN to India in January this year strongly recommended that the French group should go it alone, and not hand over ...... to an Indian Partner.', 'options': ['organised, papers', 'constituted, authority', 'sponsored, power', 'dispatched, control'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'There is a keen ...... in each trade.', 'options': ['contest', 'comparison', 'competition', 'cooperation'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Now, the management graduate can expect to have a prosperous life on a ...... income without having to depend on finding a place in family busiess having to tend the paternal estates.', 'options': ['professional', 'regular', 'meaningful', 'dependable'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The boy fell ...... bicycle.', 'options': ['of', 'off', 'from', 'under'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The French ...... reputed to have a very good sense of humour.', 'options': ['is', 'was', 'are', 'will be'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Johny, where are you? ...... up this tree.', 'options': ['There I am', 'There am I', 'Here am I', 'Here I am'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'That the poor in our country, are happy is', 'options': ['a dream', 'a vision', 'an ideal', 'an illusion'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The robbers were arrested and ...... prison yesterday.', 'options': ['brought into', 'brought to', 'taken into', 'taken to'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The cinema ...... a welcome escape from cramped and dull city life and the Indians are avid movie-goers.', 'options': ['depicts', 'highlights', 'follows', 'offers'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'I shall take revenge ...... you.', 'options': ['from', 'with', 'on', 'at'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'This book is a useful ...... to our library.', 'options': ['discovery', 'asset', 'addition', 'arrival'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'The boy was cured ...... typhoid.', 'options': ['from', 'of', 'for', 'through'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The communalist represents the ...... of everything noble that we have inherited from our culture and history.', 'options': ['antithesis', 'antidote', 'immorality', 'antagonism'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He is so ...... to light that he never leaves the house without sunglasses.', 'options': ['insensitive', 'sensitive', 'afraid', 'immune'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "The ...... of the Minister's statement cannot be verified by people who have no access to official records.", 'options': ['veracity', 'verbosity', 'ambiguity', 'validity'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'But the introductory fee does not stop after the initial handshake, brokers have to ...... it up after each transaction.', 'options': ['bring', 'cough', 'boost', 'give'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'Colgate has also set an ambitious aim of ......on 8% value shared of tooth paste market by then end of first years.', 'options': ['cornering', 'soliciting', 'disturbing', 'keeping'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '...... a failure of some traffic lights, traffic is moving very slowly.', 'options': ['Owing', 'Due to', 'Because', 'Since'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The battalion operating from the mountain was able to ...... three enemy divisons.', 'options': ['tie up', 'tie down', 'tie on', 'tie with'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'I purposely ...... meet you during my last visit to Kashmir.', 'options': ["didn't", "won't", "hadn't", "wouldn't"], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I have read one novel by Premchand. I want to read ...... novel by him.', 'options': ['other', 'another', 'all', 'few'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'A man remains narrow minded, self compliance and ignorant unless he visits other people and ...... from them.', 'options': ['earns', 'borrows', 'learns', 'hears'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'My father ...... down for a nap.', 'options': ['lays', 'laid', 'lain', 'lie'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I think they allow their children too much ......', 'options': ['liberality', 'latitude', 'lassitude', 'levity'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "Once you suspect a person of double dealing, you ought to keep him at arm's ......", 'options': ['distance', 'length', 'aim', 'width'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Affix a revenue stamp and put your signature ...... it.', 'options': ['on', 'upo', 'above', 'over'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Pick out the most effective word(s) from the given words to fill in the blank to make the sentence meaningfully complete.
[{'question': 'My first lesson ...... forgiveness came from my mother.', 'options': ['upon', 'about', 'in', 'on'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'At one point, it looked as if an area of agreement would ...... specially over the issue of productivity linked wages.', 'options': ['develop', 'come out', 'emerge', 'grow'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Do you know ......?', 'options': ['where she comes from', 'where does she come from', 'where from she comes', 'from where does she come'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'God is ......', 'options': ['graceful', 'gracious', 'grateful', 'greatful'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He is so ...... that he immediately believe my story of ghosts.', 'options': ['innocent', 'credulous', 'vociferous', 'credible'], 'answer': 'b'}]

Spellings
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Efficient', 'Treatmeant', 'Beterment', 'Employd'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Foreign', 'Foreine', 'Fariegn', 'Forein'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Ommineous', 'Omineous', 'Ominous', 'Omenous'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Pessenger', 'Passenger', 'Pasanger', 'Pesanger'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Benefitted', 'Benifited', 'Benefited', 'Benefeted'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Treachrous', 'Trecherous', 'Trechearous', 'Treacherous'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Forcast', 'Forecaste', 'Forcaust', 'Forecast'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Rigerous', 'Rigourous', 'Regerous', 'Rigorous'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Palete', 'Palet', 'Palate', 'Pelate'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Bouquete', 'Bouquette', 'Bouquet', 'Boqquet'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Vetarinary', 'Veteninary', 'Vetinary', 'Veterinary'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Chancelary', 'Chancellery', 'Chancelery', 'Chancellary'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Excessive', 'Exccessive', 'Exxcesive', 'Excesive'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Indipensable', 'Indipenseble', 'Indispansible', 'Indispensable'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Humorous', 'Ganerous', 'Pupolous', 'Maretorious'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Itinarery', 'Itinerary', 'Itenary', 'Itinarary'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Survaillance', 'Surveillance', 'Survellance', 'Surveilance'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Sepulchral', 'Sepilchrle', 'Sepalchrul', 'Sepalchrl'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Acommodation', 'Accomodaton', 'Accommodation', 'Acomodation'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Faithfuly', 'Sincerely', 'Truely', 'Affectionatly'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Klaptomania', 'Klepptomania', 'Kleptemania', 'Kleptomania'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Schedulle', 'Schedeule', 'Schdule', 'Schedule'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Skillful', 'Skillfull', 'Skilfull', 'Skilpull'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Judicious', 'Cancious', 'Dilicous', 'Gracous'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Gaurantee', 'Guarantee', 'Garuntee', 'Guaruntee'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Friming', 'Burnning', 'Running', 'Fryng'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Dammage', 'Damaige', 'Dammege', 'Damage'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Accomplish', 'Acomplush', 'Ackmplesh', 'Accompalish'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Puerrile', 'Puerrille', 'Purrile', 'Puerile'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Satelite', 'Sattelite', 'Satellite', 'Sattellite'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Inoculation', 'Innoculation', 'Inocculation', 'Inocullation'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Velnerable', 'Vulnarable', 'Vulnerable', 'Valnerable'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Simpal', 'Bannar', 'Pattren', 'Modern'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Scripher', 'Scripture', 'Skripture', 'Scriptur'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Comitte', 'Commitee', 'Committee', 'Comiittee'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Exaggerate', 'Exeggrate', 'Exagerate', 'Exadgerate'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Asspersion', 'Voluptuous', 'Voguei', 'Equestrain'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Hindrance', 'Hinderrance', 'Hindrence', 'Hinderence'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Parallelled', 'Parralleled', 'Paralleled', 'Paraleled'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Lckadaisicle', 'Lackdaisical', 'Lackadisical', 'Lackadaisical'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Equanimity', 'Equannimity', 'Equanimmity', 'Equinimity'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Occured', 'Occurad', 'Ocurred', 'Occurred'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Swelte', 'Filpant', 'Licentious', 'Puessile'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Grief', 'Breif', 'Recieve', 'Diceive'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Furnituer', 'Exampel', 'Medicine', 'Sampal'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Find the correctly spelt words.
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Eflorescence', 'Efllorescence', 'Efflorescence', 'Efflorascence'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Exterminatte', 'Inexpliccable', 'Offspring', 'Reffere'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Occasion', 'Occassion', 'Ocasion', 'Ocassion'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['Entrepreneur', 'Entrapreneur', 'Entrepraneur', 'Enterprenuer'], 'answer': 'a'}]

Sentence Formation
In each question below a sentence broken into five or six parts. Join these parts to make a meaningful sentence. The correct order of parts is the answer.
[{'question': '1. I 2. immediately 3. salary\n4. my 5. want  ', 'options': ['43152', '15432', '25143', '42351', '45132'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '1. do 2. today 3. you\n4. must 5. it  ', 'options': ['34152', '25413', '12543', '51324', '45213'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '1. left 2. the 3. house\n4. he 5. suddenly  ', 'options': ['12435', '21354', '45123', '52341', '24135'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '1. medicine 2. a 3. Neeta\n4. given 5. was  ', 'options': ['51423', '25431', '15423', '42531', '35421'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': '1. of 2. we 3. heard\n4. him 5. had  ', 'options': ['42351', '52341', '25341', '25431', '25314'], 'answer': 'e'}]
In each question below a sentence broken into five or six parts. Join these parts to make a meaningful sentence. The correct order of parts is the answer.
[{'question': '1. at 2. it 3. take\n4. once 5. away  ', 'options': ['23514', '14352', '32514', '53214', '42315'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '1. him 2. the 3. to\n4. charge 5. handover  ', 'options': ['42531', '51342', '41352', '45231', '52431'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': '1. seen 2. going 3. you\n4. him 5. have  ', 'options': ['35214', '35142', '32514', '35124', '53124'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '1. bag? 2. you 3. seen\n4. have 5. my  ', 'options': ['51432', '43512', '42351', '42153', '21435'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '1. killed 2. a 3. Jaswant\n4. bear 5. wild  ', 'options': ['31254', '53124', '23145', '43125', '15234'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In each question below a sentence broken into five or six parts. Join these parts to make a meaningful sentence. The correct order of parts is the answer.
[{'question': '1. was 2. and 3. Suresh\n4. kind 5. loving  ', 'options': ['31425', '54213', '34251', '15243', '12345'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '1. tea 2. have 3. that\n4. some 5. before  ', 'options': ['43251', '24315', '24153', '52431', '41325'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '1. not 2. hotel 3. comfortable\n4. was 5. the  ', 'options': ['34521', '53412', '34152', '41352', '52413'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': '1. I 2. help 3. not\n4. you 5. did  ', 'options': ['24351', '15324', '45231', '43152', '52431'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '1. not 2. Hari 3. away\n4. run 5. did  ', 'options': ['13542', '35412', '52431', '25143', '21345'], 'answer': 'd'}]

Ordering of Words
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'When he\nP : did not know\nQ : he was nervous and\nR : heard the hue and cry at midnight\nS : what to do\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQPS', 'QSPR', 'SQPR', 'PQRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'It has been established that\nP : Einstein was\nQ : although a great scientist\nR : weak in arithmetic\nS : right from his school days\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRPQ', 'QPRS', 'QPSR', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Then\nP : it struck me\nQ : of course\nR : suitable it was\nS : how eminently\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPQR', 'QSRP', 'PSRQ', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'I read an advertisement that said\nP : posh, air-conditioned\nQ : gentleman of taste\nR : are available for\nS : fully furnished rooms\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'PSRQ', 'PSQR', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Since the beginning of history\nP : have managed to catch\nQ : the Eskimos and Red Indians\nR : by a very difficulty method\nS : a few specimens of this aquatic animal\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'SQPR', 'SQRP', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'A French woman\nP : committed suicide\nQ : where she had put up\nR : who had come to Calcutta\nS : by jumping from the first floor balcony of the hotel\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRQS', 'QSRP', 'RPSQ', 'SRQP'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The national unity of a free people\nP : to make it impracticable\nQ : for there to be an arbitrary administration\nR : depends upon a sufficiently even balance of political power\nS : against a revolutionary opposition that is irreconcilably opposed to it\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'QRSP', 'RPQS', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The grocer\nP : did not listen to the protests of customer\nQ : who was in the habit of weighing less\nR : whom he had cheated\nS : with great audacity\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRSQ', 'QSPR', 'QPRS', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'They felt safer\nP : to watch the mountain\nQ : of more than five miles\nR : as they settled down\nS : from a distance\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPSQ', 'RSQP', 'PQSR', 'PRSQ'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'People\nP : at his dispensary\nQ : went to him\nR : of all professions\nS : for medicine and treatment\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'RPQS', 'RQSP', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'If you need help\nP : promptly and politely\nQ : ask for attendants\nR : to help our customers\nS : who have instructions\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'QPSR', 'QSRP', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It is easier\nP : to venture into space\nQ : for men\nR : beneath their feet\nS : than to explore\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'QPSR', 'PSRQ', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "It was to be\nP : before their school examination\nQ : which was due to start\nR : the last expedition\nS : in a month's\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SRQP', 'RQSP', 'RPQS', 'SPRQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'This time\nP : exactly what he had been told\nQ : the young man did\nR : beyond his dreams\nS : and the plan succeeded\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'QPSR', 'PQSR', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'In the darkness\nP : the long, narrow beard\nQ : was clearly visible with\nR : the tall stooping figure of the doctor\nS : and the aquiline nose\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQPS', 'PSQR', 'RSQP', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'We have to\nP : as we see it\nQ : speak the truth\nR : there is falsehood and weakness\nS : even if all around us\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQSP', 'QRPS', 'RSQP', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'When it began to rain suddenly on the first of January\nP : to celebrate the new year\nQ : we ran for shelter\nR : to the neighbouring house\nS : where many people had gathered\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'PSQR', 'PRSQ', 'QRSP'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'He told us that\nP : and enjoyed it immensely\nQ : in a prose translation\nR : he had read Milton\nS : which he had borrowed from his teacher\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RSQP', 'QRPS', 'RQSP', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He knew that\nP : and then to save himself\nQ : was to save all the lives\nR : entrusted to his care\nS : the duty of a captain\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'SQRP', 'SPRQ', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'It is not, therefore\nP : that I pay a tribute\nQ : to conductors as a class\nR : with any feeling of unfriendliness\nS : to a particular member of that class\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'RQPS', 'RSPQ', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'Of many artists\nP : those who impressed me the most\nQ : I was a child\nR : but those with unique personalities off stage\nS : were not always the successful ones\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'QRSP', 'RSPQ', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'As a disease\nP : and breaks up marriages\nQ : accidents and suicides\nR : alcoholism leads to\nS : affecting all ages\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRPQ', 'RPSQ', 'SRQP', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It is easy to excuse\nP : but it is hard\nQ : in a boy of fourteen\nR : the mischief of early childhood\nS : to tolerate even unavoidable faults\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'QRSP', 'QRPS', 'RPSQ'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The majestic mahogany table\nP : belongs to an old prince\nQ : which has one leg missing\nR : who is no impoverished\nS : but not without some pride\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQSR', 'QRSP', 'PRSQ', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Education is\nP : of the proper sense of responsibilities\nQ : the first need\nR : in a citizen\nS : for the development\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'QSRP', 'QSPR', 'PQRS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'It would\nP : appear from his statement\nQ : about the policy of management\nR : in dealing with the strike\nS : that he was quite in the dark\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPSQ', 'PSQR', 'RQPS', 'PRQS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He was so kind and generous that\nP : he not only\nQ : made others do so\nR : but also\nS : helped them himself\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSRQ', 'SPQR', 'PRSQ', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'We went\nP : along the railway line\nQ : and had a right to\nR : where other people not allowed to go\nS : but daddy belonged to the railway\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'PRSQ', 'RSQP', 'PRQS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'There was\nP : needed for it everyday life\nQ : a time when each family\nR : for itself most of the things it\nS : actually produced\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'RQPS', 'RSPQ', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Little\nP : that he had been let down\nQ : stood by all these years\nR : did he realise\nS : by a colleague whom he had\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPSQ', 'RSQP', 'QSRP', 'QSPR'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'I saw that\nP : but seeing my host in this mood\nQ : I deemed it proper to take leave\nR : as I had frequently done before\nS : it had been my intention to pass the night there\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPSR', 'QRPS', 'SPQR', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'It is very easy\nP : a great deal more than one realises\nQ : may mean\nR : that a phrase that one does not quite understand\nS : to persuade oneself\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RSQP', 'SPQR', 'SRQP', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'I was\nP : and stay fro few days in Delhi\nQ : when my father told me\nR : very excited\nS : that I could go with him\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'RQSP', 'QRSP', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'work is the one thing\nP : and without it\nQ : that is necessary\nR : to keep the world going\nS : we should all die\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPSR', 'RPQS', 'SRPQ', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The appearance\nP : this dinosaurs were at their peak\nQ : of the first mammals on the earth\nR : at the time when\nS : went almost unnoticed\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRPQ', 'QSRP', 'QRPS', 'RPQS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'By this time\nP : at the railway station\nQ : reported mass looting\nR : reports of violence were flooding in\nS : which police dispatches\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RSPQ', 'SPRQ', 'SQRP', 'RSQP'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Then the women\nP : lamenting their evil desire\nQ : that had brought\nR : wept loudly\nS : this sorrow upon them\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'RQPS', 'PQSR', 'PRQS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Women\nP : till the other day\nQ : who were content being housewives\nR : about spending their time cooking\nS : now sound apologetic\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'RSPQ', 'QPSR', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Though he dialled frequently\nP : on telephone\nQ : my brother could not contact me\nR : and had left no information\nS : as I had gone out of office\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'SQRP', 'QPSR', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He said\nP : here is the cat\nQ : throughout the night\nR : which had been paying havoc with things\nS : that ate the rat\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'PSRQ', 'QPRS', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'He sat\nP : through the Town Hall Park\nQ : which flanked a path running\nR : under the boughs\nS : of a spreading tamarind tree\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQSR', 'RSQP', 'RSPQ', 'PRSQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "I don't remember\nP : I saw a man dying in front of a hospital\nQ : but when I left lucknow in 1984\nR : hit apparently by a fast moving car\nS : the exact date\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SQRP', 'SQPR', 'QRPS', 'SPRQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'It was\nP : in keeping with my mood\nQ : a soft summer evening\nR : as I walked sedately\nS : in the direction of new house\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRPQ', 'QRPS', 'QPRS', 'SQPR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'All such students\nP : get success\nQ : who are honest and hard-working\nR : and recognition\nS : in very walk of life\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPRQ', 'PRQS', 'QPRS', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The master\nP : who was very loyal to him\nQ : punished the servant\nR : without giving any valid reason\nS : when he left the work unfinished\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQPS', 'RQSP', 'QPSR', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question below, there is a sentence of which some parts have been jumbled up. Rearrange these parts which are labelled P, Q, R and S to produce the correct sentence. Choose the proper sequence.
[{'question': 'With her body\nP : dragging her unwilling feet\nQ : weak and infirm\nR : doubled with age\nS : she persisted in her mission\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'QPRS', 'RQPS', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'P: We must read\nP : if we want to absorb the fruits of great literature\nQ : but with concentration\nR : them not as we do cricket stories\nS : undefined\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPSR', 'PSQR', 'PRSQ', 'PRQS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I enclose\nP : and the postage\nQ : a postal order\nR : the price of books\nS : which will cover\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPSQ', 'QSPR', 'QSRP', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Sentence Correction
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'The small child does whatever his father was done.', 'options': ['has done', 'did', 'does', 'had done', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'You need not come unless you want to.', 'options': ["You don't need to come unless you want to", 'You come only when you want to', "You come unless you don't want to", "You needn't come until you don't want to", 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'There are not many men who are so famous that they are frequently referred to by their short names only', 'options': ['initials', 'signatures', 'pictures', 'middle names', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The man to who I sold my house was a cheat.', 'options': ['to whom I sell', 'to who I sell', 'who was sold to', 'to whom I sold', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'They were all shocked at his failure in the competition.', 'options': ['were shocked at all', 'had all shocked at', 'had all shocked by', 'had been all shocked on', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'I need not offer any explanation regarding this incident - my behaviour is speaking itself.', 'options': ['will speak to itself', 'speaks for itself', 'has been speaking', 'speaks about itself', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He is too important for tolerating any delay.', 'options': ['to tolerate', 'to tolerating', 'at tolerating', 'with tolerating', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The population of Tokyo is greater than that of any other town in the world.', 'options': ['greatest among any other', 'greater than all other', 'greater than those of any other', 'greater than any other', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The performance of our players was rather worst than I had expected.', 'options': ['bad as I had expected', 'worse than I had expected', 'worse than expectation', 'worst than was expected', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Why did you not threw the bag away?', 'options': ['did you not throw', 'had you not threw', 'did you not thrown', 'you did not thrown', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'Shapes of gods and goddess are worshipped by people.', 'options': ['Images', 'Reflections', 'Clay shapes', 'Clay toys', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'In addition to enhanced their reputations through strategic use of philanthropy, companies are sponsoring social initiatives to open new markets.', 'options': ['of enhancing their reputation', 'to having enhance their reputation', 'to enhancing their reputation', 'to have their reputation enhancing', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The intruder stood quietly for few moments', 'options': ['for few time', 'for the few moments', 'for moments', 'for a few moments', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The police has so far succeeded in recovering only a part of the stolen property.', 'options': ['thus far succeeded for recovery', 'so far succeeded in recovery of', 'as for as succeeded in recovery of', 'so far succeeded to recover', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'He confidentially asked the crowd if they thought he was right and the crowd shouted that they did.', 'options': ['that he did', 'that they had', 'that he is', "that he didn't", 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'Why should the candidates be afraid of English Language is not clear.', 'options': ['the candidates should be', 'do the candidates be', 'should be the candidates', 'are the candidates', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He found the gold coin as he cleans the floor.', 'options': ['as he had cleaned', 'while he cleans', 'which he is cleaning', 'while cleaning', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'He admired the speed with which he completed the work and appreciating the method adopted by him', 'options': ['appreciate the method being adopted', 'appreciated the method adopted', 'appreciate the method of adoption', 'appreciated the method adopting method', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Maria unnecessarily picked up a quarrel with Rani and left the party hurried.', 'options': ['has picked up', 'picked on', 'picked', 'picking up', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'She cooks, washes dishes, does her homework and then relaxing.', 'options': ['relaxing then', 'then is relaxing', 'relaxing is then', 'then relaxes', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'Acquisition of certain specific skills can be facilitated from general awareness, education to novel situations', 'options': ['can be facilitated by', 'may facilitate through', 'can be felicitated with', 'may be felicitated with', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He never has and ever will take such strong measures.', 'options': ['had taken nor will ever take', 'had taken and will ever take', 'has and never will take', 'had and ever will take', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Technology must use to feed the forces of change.', 'options': ['must be used to feed', 'must have been using to feed', 'must use having fed', 'must be using to feed', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Anyone interested in the use of computers can learn much if you have access to a personal computer.', 'options': ['they have access', 'access can be available', 'he or she has access', 'one of them have access', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'They are not beware of all the facts', 'options': ['are not aware for', 'are not aware of', 'are not to be aware', 'must not to be aware for', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'We can not always convey ourselves in simple sentences.', 'options': ['cannot always convey', 'can not always express', 'cannot always express', 'can not always communicate', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'What does agonise me most is not this criticism, but the trivial reason behind it.', 'options': ['most agonising me', 'agonises me most', 'agonising me most', 'I most agonised', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'As there was no time, the remaining items were deferred into the next meeting.', 'options': ['are deferred till', 'were deferred till', 'were deferred to', 'had deferred with', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Despite of their differences on matters of principles, they all agree on the demand of hike is salary?', 'options': ['Despite their', 'Despite of the', 'Despite for their', 'Despite off their', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The man who has committed such a serious crime must get the mostly severe punishment.', 'options': ['be getting the mostly severely', 'get the most severe', 'have got the most severely', 'have been getting the severe most', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'For many centuries in Indian History there was no city so famous like the city of Ujjain.', 'options': ['as', 'such as', 'likewise', 'so like', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "We don't know how did the thief made an escape.", 'options': ['how the thief did make', 'how the thief does make', 'how the thief made', 'how was the thief made', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "He is a singer of repute, but his yesterday's performance was quite disappointing.", 'options': ['performances of yesterday were', 'yesterday performance was', 'yesterday performance were', 'performances about yesterday were', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Their earnings are such that they find it difficult to make both ends to meet.', 'options': ['to makings both ends meet', 'to make both ends for meeting', 'to make both ends meet', 'for making both ends to meet', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He has received no other message than an urgent telegram asking him to rush his village immediately.', 'options': ['asked him to rush his village', 'asking him to have rush his village', 'asking him to rush to his village', 'asking him rushing at his village', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'One of the most significant phenomenons of our time has been the development of cinema.', 'options': ['phenomenon', 'phenomena', 'phenomenonna', 'phenomenonns', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Had you been told me about your problem, I would have helped you.', 'options': ['If you would have told', 'Had you have told', 'had you told', 'If you have told', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It was until many years later that Gandhi became a rebel against authority.', 'options': ['It was not until many years', 'It was till many years', 'It was not many years', 'Until It was many years', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Anand has the guts to rise from the occasion and come out successfully.', 'options': ['in rising from', 'to raise with', 'to rise to', 'to rise against', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "If you are thinking about investigation overseas, isn't it makes sense to find an experience guide?", 'options': ['it is not making', "doesn't it make", 'does it make', 'is it making', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'This is one of the most important inventions of this century.', 'options': ['invention of this century', 'invention of these century', 'invention of centuries', 'invention of the centuries', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The orator had been left the auditorium before the audience stood up.', 'options': ['had been leaving', 'was left', 'had left', 'would leave', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "He dislikes the word dislike, isn't he", 'options': ["didn't he", "doesn't he", "hasn't he", 'does he', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "We must take it granted that Madhu will not come for today's function.", 'options': ['take it for granted', 'taking it granted', 'took it as granted', 'have it granted', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The research study is an eye-opener and attempts to acquaint us with the problems of poor nations.', 'options': ['attempted to acquaint', 'attempts at acquainting', 'attempt to acquaint', 'attempting to acquaint', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'It was unanimously resolved that the parties should unitedly undertook launching of popular programmes.', 'options': ['should be united undertook', 'should be unitedly undertaken', 'should be unitedly undertake', 'should unitedly undertake', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'They continued to work in the field despite of the heavy rains.', 'options': ['even though there is heavy rain', 'although heavily rains', 'in spite the heavy rains', 'even though it rained heavily', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'It is always better to make people realise the importance of discipline than to impose them on it.', 'options': ['impose it with them', 'impose them with it', 'imposing them on it', 'impose it on them', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'My doctor knew that I would eventually recover and do kind of work I would be doing before', 'options': ['would have been doing', 'would have done', 'had been done', 'had been doing', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Later he became unpopular because he tried to lord it on his followers.', 'options': ['to lord it for', 'to lord over', 'to lord it over', 'to lord it over on', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'The crops are dying; it must not had rained.', 'options': ['must had not', 'must not be', 'must not have', 'must not have been', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The courts are actively to safeguard the interests and the rights of the poor.', 'options': ['are actively to safeguarding', 'have been actively safeguarding', 'have to active in safeguarding', 'are actively in safeguarding', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The drama had many scenes which were so humorous that it was hardly possible to keep a straight face.', 'options': ['hardly possible for keeping', 'hardly impossible for keeping', 'hardly impossible for keep', 'hardly possible keeping', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Hardly does the sun rise when the stars disappeared.', 'options': ['have the sun rose', 'had the sun risen', 'did the sun rose', 'the sun rose', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'You will be late if you do not leave now', 'options': ['did not leave', 'left', 'will not leave', 'do not happen to leave', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'The train will leave at 8.30 pm, we have been ready by 7.30pm so that, we can reach the station in time.', 'options': ['were', 'must be', 'are', 'should have', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'All the allegations levelled against him were found to be baseless.', 'options': ['level against', 'level with', 'levelling with', 'levelled for', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Ramesh is as tall if not, taller than Mahesh.', 'options': ['not as tall but', 'not so tall but as', 'as tall as, if not', 'as if not', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He hesitated to listen to what his brother was saying.', 'options': ['listened to hesitate', 'hesitated listen to', 'hesitates to listening', 'is hesitated to listen to', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The prosecution failed in establish in every case today.', 'options': ['to', 'on', 'as', 'upon', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'One of my drawbacks is that I do not have to tolerance of ambiguity.', 'options': ['do not have', 'cannot have', 'am not', 'did not have to', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'They should have calmly thought of the advantages that would accrue to them.', 'options': ['should have been calm in thinking about', 'should be calmly thought of', 'shall have to calmly thought of', 'should have calmly think of', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The easiest of the thing to do is to ask the address to the postman.', 'options': ['of the things to do', 'among the things did', 'of the thing to be done', 'of all the things done', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'We demonstrated to them how we were prepared the artistic patterns.', 'options': ['are prepared', 'have prepared', 'are preparing', 'had prepared', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Because of his mastery in this field, his suggestions are wide accepted.', 'options': ['are widely accepted', 'widely acceptance', 'have widely accepted', 'have been wide accepted', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'They felt humiliated because they realised that they had cheated.', 'options': ['have been cheated', 'had been cheated', 'had been cheating', 'were to be cheated', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Tax evaders should heavily punished as they do it intentionally.', 'options': ['should be heavy fined', 'should have heavily fined', 'shall have heavy fine', 'should be heavily fined', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'We met him immediately after the session in which he had been given a nice speech.', 'options': ['would be giving', 'has been given', 'will have given', 'had given', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'For some days the new professor lectured above the heads of his pupils.', 'options': ['over the head of', 'over the heads of', 'on the heads of', 'through the heds of', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The accused now flatly denies have admitted his guilt in his first statement.', 'options': ['having admitted', 'had admitted', 'have been admitting', 'has admitting', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'We were still standing in the queue when the film was beginning.', 'options': ['film began', 'film had begun', 'beginning of the film was over', 'film begins', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If I would have realised the nature of job earlier, I would not have accepted it.', 'options': ['If I have had', 'In case I would have', 'Had I been', 'Had I', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The crime has growth rapidly in Russia since the disintegration of the communist system.', 'options': ['rapid crime has grown', 'crime has grown rapidly', 'crimes grow rapidly', 'crimes have been rapidly grown', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'They failed in their attempt to repair the demolished portion of that building.', 'options': ['for their attempt to repair', 'in their attempting to repair', 'with their attempt to repair', 'in their attempt for repairs', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'I earnestly believe that you will visit our relatives during your forthcoming trip to Mumbai.', 'options': ['had hardly believe that', 'sincerely would believe', 'certainly believing that', 'could not believe', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'By such time you finish that chapter, I will write a letter.', 'options': ['The time when', 'By the time', 'By that time', 'The time', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Though we have kept in mind to try and maintain most facilities, we would like to request you to kindly bear with us any inconvenience that may be caused.', 'options': ['must keep in mind to try and maintain', 'have kept in mind trying and maintain', 'would keep in mind to try and to maintain', 'should have kept in mind to try and to maintain', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The tea-estate administration is in such mess there is no leader to set the things right.', 'options': ['in such a mess here', 'in a such mess that here', 'in such a mess that there', 'with such a mess that there', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'They examined both the samples very carefully but failed to detect any difference in them.', 'options': ['some difference in', 'some difference between', 'any difference between', 'any difference among', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '"Friends and comrades, the light has gone away from our lives and there is darkness everywhere"', 'options': ['off', 'out of', 'out from', 'out off', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'Because of his ill health, the doctor has advised him not to refrain from smoking.', 'options': ['to not refrain from', 'to resort to', 'to refrain from', 'to be refrained from', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'They have a scheme of rewarding the best of the performers every year.', 'options': ['a best performer', 'the best among the performer', 'a best among performer', 'the best of the performer', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'What happens to all those travellers on the ship was not known?', 'options': ['What happened of', 'What happened in', 'What is that happens to', 'What happened to', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Making friends is more rewarding than to make enemies.', 'options': ['to be unsociable', 'to be sociable', 'being unsociable', 'making enemies', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The moment they saw me, they were delight', 'options': ['had delighted', 'were delighted', 'are delighted', 'have been delighted', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'He should not had done it.', 'options': ['had not', 'should had not', 'should not have', 'should have', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'No sooner do the bells ring than the curtain rose.', 'options': ['did the bell ring', 'did the bells ring', 'had the bell rang', 'had the bell rung', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The moment the manager came to know fraudulent action of his assistant, he order immediately dismissed him.', 'options': ['immediately ordered his dismissed', 'ordered his immediate dismissal', 'immediately order dismissal of his', 'ordered for immediately dismissal of him', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The meeting was attended to by all invitees.', 'options': ['all attended to by', 'attended by all', 'fully attended to by', 'like attending to all', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If he has to spend five hours in the queue, it was really a wastage.', 'options': ['is a really wastage', 'is real a wastage', 'has really a wastage', 'is really a wastage', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'The world has seen small real attempt at population and resource planning.', 'options': ['few', 'little', 'less', 'a few', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'My hair stood off ends when I saw the horrible sight.', 'options': ['stood at ends', 'stood on ends', 'stood to ends', 'stands on ends', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The long or short of it is that I do not want to deal with that new firm.', 'options': ['The long and short of it', 'The long and short for it', 'The long or short for it', 'The shot and long for it', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Can you tell me why did you not speak the truth?', 'options': ['why did not you speak', 'that why did you not speak', 'why you did not speak', 'why did you not spoke', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The people generally try to curry favour with the corrupt but influential person.', 'options': ['cook favour', 'seek favour', 'extract favour', 'display favour', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]
Which of phrases given below each sentence should replace the phrase printed in bold type to make the grammatically correct? If the sentence is correct as it is, mark 'E' as the answer.
[{'question': 'I have got some tea, but I do not have a sugar.', 'options': ['some', 'got', 'more', 'any', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Had I realised how close I was to the edge of the valley, I would not have carried the bags there.', 'options': ['Had I been realised', 'If I would have realised', 'When I realised', 'Had I had realised', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Most of the Indian workers are as healthy as, if not healthier than, British workers.', 'options': ['as if healthy as not healthier', 'healthier but not as healthy', 'as healthy, if not healthier', 'so healthy, if not healthier', 'No correction required'], 'answer': 'e'}]

Sentence Improvement
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'The workers are hell bent at getting what is due to them.', 'options': ['hell bent on getting', 'hell bent for getting', 'hell bent upon getting', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'When it was feared that the serfs might go too far and gain their freedom from serfdom, the protestant leaders joined the princes at crushing them.', 'options': ['into crushing', 'in crushing', 'without crushing', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If the room had been brighter, I would have been able to read for a while before bed time.', 'options': ['If the room was brighter', 'If the room are brighter', 'Had the room been brighter', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The record for the biggest tiger hunt has not been met since 1911 when Lord Hardinge. then Viceroy of India, shot a tiger than measured 11 feet and 6 inches.', 'options': ['improved', 'broken', 'bettered', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'his powerful desire brought about his downfall.', 'options': ['His intense desire', 'His desire for power', 'His fatal desire', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Will you kindly open the knot?', 'options': ['untie', 'break', 'loose', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He sent a word to me that he would be coming late.', 'options': ['sent word', 'had sent a word', 'sent words', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "John had told me that he hasn't done it yet.", 'options': ['told', 'tells', 'was telling', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If he had time he will call you.', 'options': ['would have', 'would have had', 'has', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Will you lend me few rupees in this hour of need?', 'options': ['lend me any rupees', 'borrow me a few rupees', 'lend me a few rupees', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'During his long discourse, he did not touch that point.', 'options': ['touch upon', 'touch on', 'touch of', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He found a wooden broken chair in the room.', 'options': ['wooden and broken chair', 'broken wooden chair', 'broken and wooden chair', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He could not look anything in the dark room.', 'options': ['look at', 'see', 'see through', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The greatest thing in style is to have a use of metaphor.', 'options': ['knowledge', 'command', 'need', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'While crossing the highway a five year old child was knocked out by a passing car.', 'options': ['away', 'up', 'down', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'hoping not to be disturbed, I sat down in my easy chair to read the book. I won as a prize.', 'options': ['I had won as a prize', 'I have won as prize', 'I had to win as a prize', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'More than one person was killed in accident.', 'options': ['were killed', 'are killed', 'have been killed', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'No one could explain how a calm and balanced person like him could penetrate such a mindless act on his friends.', 'options': ['perpetuate', 'perpetrate', 'precipitate', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Five years ago today, I am sitting in a small Japanese car, driving across Poland towards Berlin.', 'options': ['was sitting', 'sat', 'have been sitting', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I took the cycle which he bought yesterday.', 'options': ['that he bought yesterday', 'that which he had bought yesterday', 'that he had bought yesterday', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Please make it a point to send you letter at my address.', 'options': ['on my address', 'to my address', 'in my address', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If you are living near a market place you should be ready to bear the disturbances caused by traffic.', 'options': ['to bear upon', 'to bear with', 'to bear away', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "I hope you won't object to me watching while you work.", 'options': ['against me watching', 'me to watch', 'to my watching', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'You cannot forbid him leaving.', 'options': ['he leaving', 'his leaving', 'him to leave', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '20 kms are not a great distance in these days of fast moving vehicles.', 'options': ['is not a great distance', 'is no distance', "aren't a great distance", 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'The more they earn, more they spend.', 'options': ['More they earn, more they spend', 'More they earn, the more they spend', 'The more they earn, the more they spend', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It became clear that the strangers were heading into a serious disaster.', 'options': ['along', 'towards', 'for', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The dissidents hold a great problem in every political party.', 'options': ['cause', 'give', 'pose', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I would have waited for you at the station if I knew that you would come.', 'options': ['had known', 'was knowing', 'have known', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'They are social insects, living in communities, regulated by definite laws, each member of society bearing well-defined and separate part in the work of a colony.', 'options': ['who are living in communities', 'living among a community', 'who lives with a community', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Practically every part of the banana tree is used by man.', 'options': ['each part', 'any part', 'most part', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'My opinion for the film is that it will bag the national ward.', 'options': ['opinion to', 'opinion about', 'opinion on', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The end of the examinations is (an) oppurtunity for celebrating.', 'options': ['chance', 'moment', 'occasion', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'We were not the wiser for all this effort to explain the case to us.', 'options': ['none', 'neither', 'nevertheless', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Whenever my students come across new words, I ask them to look for them in the dictionary.', 'options': ['to look it up', 'to look them up', 'to look at them', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'We look forward to hear from you.', 'options': ['hearing', 'have heard', 'listen', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'It was indeed a shock for her, but she has later recovered from it.', 'options': ['since', 'then', 'afterwards', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Realising is the significance of technical education for developing country, the government laid aside a large sum on it during the last plan-period.', 'options': ['laid up', 'set aside', 'laid out', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'If you are not clear about the meaning of a word, it is wise to look to a dictionary.', 'options': ['look for', 'look at', 'look up', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'You are warned against committing the same mistake again.', 'options': ['to commit', 'for committing', 'against to commit', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'No sooner he had returned home then his mother felt happy.', 'options': ['had he returned home when', 'he had returned home than', 'did he return home than', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He should move on to the next point, and not harp one sting only.', 'options': ['harp on string only', 'harp only one string', 'harp upon one string only', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Either he or I am going.', 'options': ['he or I are going', 'he is going or I am', 'I or he is going', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'I hope you vividly remember the premier of the film when I, my wife and you were present in the hall.', 'options': ['my wife, I and you', 'you, I and my wife', 'my wife, you and I', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "To get one's name in the Rowland Ward's book of hunting records was the hot ambition of every serious hunter.", 'options': ['extreme', 'burning', 'high', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Taxpayers are to be conscious of their privileges.', 'options': ['have to', 'need', 'ought to', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'As she was suffering from high fever, she could not face the examination.', 'options': ['bear', 'suffer', 'take', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The demonstration passed off peacefully.', 'options': ['passed out', 'passed away', 'passed on', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Every time I go in a lift to my sixth floor apartment, I remember the calm and serenity of my ancestral home in the village.', 'options': ['move in a lift', 'ascend in a lift', 'take a lift', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "In fact, if it hadn't been for his invaluable advice on so many occasions I wouldn't have achieved anything in life.", 'options': ['remarkable advice', 'valuable advices', 'priceless suggestion', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Mr. Smith arrived at India in June last year.', 'options': ['to', 'by', 'in', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'But in all these cases conversion from scale have well-formulated.', 'options': ['can be well-formulated', 'are well-formulated', 'well-formulated', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'With a thundering roar the huge rocket soared up from the launching pad.', 'options': ['flew up', 'went upwards', 'took off', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'There is dearth of woman doctor in our state. We shall have to recruit some from the other states.', 'options': ['women doctor', 'woman doctors', 'women doctors', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'If you cross the line you will be disqualified.', 'options': ['cross upon the line', 'cross on the line', 'cross out the line', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Why the dinosaurs died out is not known.', 'options': ['it is not known', 'the reason is not known', 'that is not known', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "His father won't be able to leave for Varnasi until they have arrived.", 'options': ['until they arrive', 'until they will have arrived', 'until they will arrive', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I will not go to school, if it shall rain tomorrow.', 'options': ['it would rain tomorrow', 'it will rain tomorrow', 'it rains tomorrow', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'If I stood alone in defence of truth, and the whole world is banded against me and against truth. I would fight them all.', 'options': ['will be banded', 'were banded', 'banded', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He has not and can never be in the good books of his employer because he lacks honesty.', 'options': ['has not and cannot be', 'has not and can never been', 'has not been and can never be', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'When the examinations were over Anil and me went to our native town.', 'options': ['me and Anil', 'Anil and I', 'I and Anil', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Our office clock is not so correct as it should be it is usually five minutes fast.', 'options': ['right', 'regular', 'accurate', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The cloud of misfortunes appears to have blown out.', 'options': ['over', 'up', 'away', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'While we would like that all Indian Children to go to school, we need to ponder why they do not.', 'options': ['that all the Indian children', 'if all the children of India', 'all Indian children', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'In India today many of our intellectuals still talk in terms of the French Revolution and the Rights of Man, not appreciating that much has happened since then.', 'options': ['much has been happening', 'much had happened', 'much might happen', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'I shall be grateful to you if you are of help to me now.', 'options': ['help', 'would help', 'helped', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The logic of Berlin wall already had been undermined but when the news came through that the wall itself had been opened I jumped into a car.', 'options': ['had been undetermined already', 'had already been undetermined', 'had been already undetermined', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Other countries have eradicated this disease ten years ago.', 'options': ['eradicated', 'had eradicated', 'did eradicated', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Young men and women should get habituated to reading and writing about current affairs.', 'options': ['used', 'prepared', 'trained', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The poor villagers have waited in the bitter cold for more than 4 hours now.', 'options': ['have been waiting', 'had waited', 'has been waiting', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'The old man felled some trees in the garden with hardly no effort at all.', 'options': ['hard effort', 'hardly any effort', 'a hardly any effort', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The company goes to great length to ensure that employees can be comfortable in their work environment.', 'options': ['are comfortable', 'will be comfortable', 'should be comfortable', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "I want you to clearly understand that excuses won't do", 'options': ['you clearly to understand', 'you to understand clearly', 'to clearly understand you', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'He was fined for careless driving.', 'options': ['got fined', 'fined', 'was to be fined', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Although India is still by far a poor country, it can become rich if its natural and human resources are fully utilised.', 'options': ['few and far between', 'by and large', 'by and by', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'The reason why he wrote the letter was because he could not contact him over the phone.', 'options': ['why he wrote the letter was since', 'for which he wrote the letter because', 'why he wrote the letter was that', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'As he is past his teens now, he can look for himself.', 'options': ['after', 'to', 'around', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'There is no more room for you in this compartment.', 'options': ['there is no more seat', 'there is no more space', 'there is no more accommodation', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Most donors would seriously protest any effort to extrapolate from such limited data.', 'options': ['protest against', 'protest at', 'protest to', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "She says she's already paid me back, but I can't remember, so I 'll have to take her word.", 'options': ['to take her word true', 'to take her at her word', 'to take her word for it', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'If you had attended the meeting, you would have benefited a great deal.', 'options': ['could benefit', 'would benefit', 'benefited', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'This matter admits of no excuse.', 'options': ['admits to', 'admits from', 'admits', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'If he would have tried he would have succeeded.', 'options': ['is tried', 'was tried', 'had tried', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'It will be no good trying to find an excuse next time.', 'options': ['to try to find', 'to try finding', 'trying finding', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Please remind me of posting these letters to my relatives.', 'options': ['by posting', 'to post', 'for posting', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'Not a word they spoke to the unfortunate wife about it', 'options': ['did they speak', 'they will speak', 'they had spoken', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Not long back, in Japan, a mysterious nerve gas affected a large number of people.', 'options': ['effected', 'infected', 'infested', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "We had nothing to eat since 8'o clock, this morning.", 'options': ['have had nothing', 'has had nothing', 'did have nothing', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'We did not see this movie yet.', 'options': ['have seen', 'have not seen', 'have seen', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'My friend was in hospital for a week after an accident.', 'options': ['through', 'following', 'for', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'All, but her, had made an attempt.', 'options': ['All, but she,', 'All, but herself,', 'All, but her,', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Whatever to our other problems. we have no shortcoming to cheap labour in India.', 'options': ['default', 'deficit', 'scarcity', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'I have lived in Delhi since I was four.', 'options': ['am living', 'lived', 'had lived', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'This telephone number is not existing.', 'options': ['has not existed', 'does not exist', 'has not been existing', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'I shall not go untill I am invited.', 'options': ['till I am invited', 'Unless I am invited', 'if not I am invited', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below, a part of the sentence is italicised and underlined. Below are given alternatives to the italicised part which may improve the sentence. Choose the correct alternative. In case no improvement is needed, option 'D' is the answer.
[{'question': 'He died in the year 1960 at 11pm on 14 July.', 'options': ['on 14 July in the year 1960 at 11pm', 'in the year 1960 on 14 July at 11pm', 'at 11pm on 14 July in the year 1960', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Due to these reason we are all in favour of universal compulsory education.', 'options': ['Out of these reasons', 'For these reasons', 'By these reasons', 'No improvement'], 'answer': 'b'}]

Completing Statements
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'Despite his best efforts to conceal his anger ......', 'options': ['we could detect that he was very happy', 'he failed to give us an impression of his agony', 'he succeeded in camouflaging his emotions', 'he could succeed in doing it easily', 'people came to know that he was annoyed'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Even if it rains I shall come means ......', 'options': ['if I come it will not rain', 'if it rains I shall not come', 'I will certainly come whether it rains or not', 'whenever there is rain I shall come', 'I am less likely to come if it rains'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'His appearance is unsmiling but ......', 'options': ['his heart is full of compassion for others', 'he looks very serious on most occasions', 'people are afraid of him', 'he is uncompromising on matters of task performance', 'he is full of jealousy towards his colleagues'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'She never visits any zoo because she is strong opponent of the idea of ......', 'options': ['setting the animals free into forest', 'feeding the animals while others are watching', 'watching the animals in their natural abode', 'going out of the house on a holiday', 'holding the animals in captivity for our joy'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'I felt somewhat more relaxed ......', 'options': ['but tense as compared to earlier', 'and tense as compared to earlier', 'as there was already no tension at all', 'and tension-free as compared to earlier', 'because the worry had already captured by mind'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'It is not easy to remain tranquil when those around you ......', 'options': ['behave in a socially acceptable manner', 'exhibit pleasant mannerism', 'are losing their heads', 'agree to whatever you say', 'exhibit generous and magnanimous gestures'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '"The food in this hotel is no match to what were forced at late hours in Hotel Kohinoor " means ......', 'options': ['The food in this hotel is quite good compared to what we ate at kohinoor', 'Hotel kohinoor served us good quality food than what we get here', 'Both hotels have maintained good quality of food', 'Both hotels serve poor quality of food', 'it is better to eat food than remain hungry'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Although initial investigations pointed towards him ......', 'options': ['the preceding events corroborated his involvement in the crime', 'the additional information confirmed his guilt', 'the subsequent events established that he was guilt', 'the subsequent events proved that he was innocent', 'he gave an open confession of his crime'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The weather outside was extremely pleasant and hence we decided to ......', 'options': ['utilise our time in watching the television', 'refrain from going out for a morning walk', 'enjoy a morning ride in the open', 'employ this rare opportunity for writing letters', 'remain seated in our rooms in the bungalow'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '"It is an uphill task but you will have to do it" means ......', 'options': ['The work is above the hill and you will have to do it', 'It is a very easy task but you must do it', 'It is very difficult task but you have to do it', 'This work is not reserved for you but you will have to do it', 'It is almost impossible for others but you can do it'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': '" You are thinking very highly about Ravi but he is not so" means ......', 'options': ['Ravi is as good as you think about him', 'You have a good opinion about Ravi but he is not as good as you think', 'Your view about Ravi is philosophical, keep it up', 'Ravi is much better, than what you think of him', 'You have a good opinion about Ravi but he does not have a good opinion about you'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '"Anand stuck up a friendship with Mahesh in just 2 days" means ......', 'options': ['Anand friendship with Mahesh came to an end recently', 'Anand found out the other friends of Mahesh', 'Anand fixed a deal with Mahesh in 2 days', "Anand's friendship with Mahesh lasted for 2 years", 'Anand became a friend of Mahesh in less than 2 days'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Although, he is reputed for making very candid statements ......', 'options': ['his today speech was not fairly audible', 'his promises had always been realistic', 'his speech was very interesting', 'people follow whatever he instructs to them', "his today's statements were very ambiguous"], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'The manager would like you to help Dhiraj, means ......', 'options': ['the manager would like you if you help Dhiraj', 'the manager desires you to help Dhiraj', 'the manager likes you because you help Dhiraj', 'Dhiraj expects the manager to tell you to help him', 'it will be a help to the manager if you like Dhiraj'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Owing to the acute power shortage, the people of our locality have decided to ......', 'options': ['dispense with other non-conventional energy sources', 'resort to abundant use of electricity for illumination', 'off-switch the electrical appliance while not in use', 'explore other avenues for utilising the excess power', 'resort to use of electricity only when it is inevitable'], 'answer': 'e'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'He has no money now ......', 'options': ['although he was very poor once', 'as he has given up all his wealth', 'because he was very rich once', 'because he has received huge donation', 'because he was very greedy about wealth'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He is so lazy that he ......', 'options': ['cannot depend on others for getting his work done', 'cannot delay the schedule of completing the work', 'can seldom complete his work on time', 'dislike to postpone the work that he undertakes to do', 'always help others to complete their work'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Dinesh is as stupid as he is lazy means ......', 'options': ['Dinesh is stupid because he is lazy', 'Dinesh is lazy because he is stupid', 'Dinesh is either stupid or lazy', 'Dinesh is hardly stupid but he is lazy', 'Dinesh is equally stupid and lazy'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Practically, very little work could be completed in the last week as it was ......', 'options': ['full of working days', 'a very hectic week', 'full of holidays', 'a very busy week', 'loaded with work'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Because he believes in democratic principles, he always ......', 'options': ['decides all the matters himself', 'listen to others views and enforces his own', 'shown respect to others opinions if they match his own', 'reconciles with the majority views and gives us his own', 'imposes his own views on others'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'With great efforts his son succeeded in convincing him not to donate his entire wealth to an orphanage ......', 'options': ['and lead the life of a wealthy merchant', 'but to a home for the forsaken children', 'and make an orphan of himself', 'as the orphanage needed a lot of donations', 'as the orphanage had been set up by him'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The employer appeared to be in such an affable mood that Rohit ......', 'options': ['decided to ask for a raise in his salary', 'was scared to talk to him about his leave', 'felt very guilty for his inadvertent slip', 'promised him that he would not commit mistake again', 'was pained to press his demand for a new flat.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "He always stammers in public meetings, but his today's speech ......", 'options': ['was fairly audible to everyone present in the hall', 'was not received satisfactorily', 'could not be understood properly', 'was not liked by the audience', 'was free from that defect'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Even though it is very large house, ......', 'options': ['there is a lot of space available in it for children', 'there is hardly any space available for children', 'there is no dearth of space for children', 'the servants take a long time to clean it', 'the municipal taxes on it are very happy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'It was an extremely pleasant surprise for the hutment-dweller when the Government officials told him that ......', 'options': ['he had to vacate hutment which he had been unauthorisedly occupying', 'he had been gifted with a furnished apartment in a multi-storeyed building', 'he would be arrested for wrongfully encroaching on the pavement outside his dwelling', 'they would not accede to his request', 'they had received the orders from the court to take possession of all his belongings'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'In order to help the company attain its goal of enhancing profit, all the employees ......', 'options': ['urged the management to grant paid leave', 'appealed the management to implement new welfare schemes', 'voluntarily offered to work overtime with lucrative compensation', 'voluntarily offered to render additional services in lieu of nothing', 'decided to enhance production at the cost of quality of the product'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': '"Whatever Dev uttered was without rhyme or reason" means ......', 'options': ['Dev could not recite any poem or speech', 'Dev said something which has no meaning, it was totally baseless', 'Dev was talking something which was beyond our experience', 'Dev spoke flatly without any emotion or reason', 'Dev did not refer to any poem to support his statements'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'He tames animals because he ......', 'options': ['is fond of them', 'hates them', 'is afraid of them', 'want to set them free', 'seldom loves them'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Mahesh need not have purchased the bag, means ......', 'options': ['it was not necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag but he has purchased it', 'it was necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag and he has not purchased it', 'it was not necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag and he has not purchased it', 'it was necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag but he has not purchased it', 'Mahesh already has a bag but still he purchased another one'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "In order to raise company's profit, the employees ......", 'options': ['demanded two additional increments', 'decided to go on paid holidays', 'requested the management to implement new welfare schemes', 'offered to work overtime without any compensation', 'decided to raise the cost of raw material'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In each question, an incomplete statement (Stem) followed by fillers is given. Pick out the best one which can complete incomplete stem correctly and meaningfully.
[{'question': 'The officer who had neglected to files his income tax returns had to ......', 'options': ['return the files', 'pay a fine', 'be rewarded', 'play mischief', 'give warning'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Unless you work harder you will fail, means ......', 'options': ['if you fail you will work harder', 'you must at least plan well than you will not fail', 'hardly you will fail if you do not desire so', 'if you do not put more efforts, then you will fail', 'if you only work and work alone, you will fail'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'His behaviour is so unpredictable that he ......', 'options': ['never depends upon others for getting his work done', 'is seldom trusted by others', 'always finds it difficult to keep his word', 'always insists on getting the work completed on time', 'seldom trusts others as far as the work schedule is concerned'], 'answer': 'b'}]

Ordering of Sentences
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': "S1: In the middle of one side of the square sits the Chairman of the committee, the most important person in the room.\nP : For a committee is not just a mere collection of individuals.\nQ : On him rests much of the responsibility for the success or failure of the committee.\nR : While this is happening we have an opportunity to get the 'feel' of this committe.\nS : As the meeting opens, he runs briskly through a number of formalities.\nS6: From the moment its members meet, it begins to have a sort nebulous life of its own.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['RSQP', 'PQRS', 'SQPR', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "S1: A force of exists between everybody in the universe.\nP : Normally it is very small but when the one of the bodies is a planet, like earth, the force is considerable.\nQ : It has been investigated by many scientists including Galileo and Newton.\nR : Everything on or near the surface of the earth is attracted by the mass of earth.\nS : This gravitational force depends on the mass of the bodies involved.\nS6: The greater the mass, the greater is the earth's force of attraction on it. We can call this force of attraction gravity.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['PRQS', 'PRSQ', 'QSRP', 'QSPR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: Calcutta unlike other cities kepts its trams.\nP : As a result there horrendous congestion.\nQ : It was going to be the first in South Asia.\nR : They run down the centre of the road\nS : To ease in the city decided to build an underground railway line.\nS6: The foundation stone was laid in 1972.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRSQ', 'PSQR', 'SQRP', 'RPSQ'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "S1: For some time in his youth Abraham Lincoln was manager for a shop.\nP : Then a chance Customer would come.\nQ : Young Lincoln way of keeping shop was entirely unlike anyone else's\nR : Lincoln would jump up and attend to his needs and then revert to his reading.\nS : He used to lie full length on the counter of the shop eagerly reading a book.\nS6: Never before had Lincoln had so much time for reading as had then.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SRQP', 'QSPR', 'SQRP', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: All the land was covered by the ocean.\nP : The leading god fought the monster, killed it and chopped its body in to two halves.\nQ : A terrible monster prevented the gods from separating the land from the water.\nR : The god made the sky out of the upper part of the body and ornamented it with stars.\nS : The god created the earth from the lower part, grew plants on it and populated it with animals.\nS6: The god moulded the first people out of clay according to his own image and mind.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'PQSR', 'QPSR', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Smoke oozed up between the planks.\nP : Passengers were told to be ready to quit the ship.\nQ : The rising gale fanned the smouldering fire.\nR : Everyone now knew there was fire on board.\nS : Flames broke out here and there.\nS6: Most people bore the shock bravely.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'QPSR', 'RSPQ', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: You know my wife, Madhavi, always urged me to give up smoking.\nP : I really gave it up.\nQ : And so When I went to jail I said to myself I really must give it up, if for no other reason than of being self-reliant.\nR : When I emerged from jail, I wanted to tell her of my great triumph.\nS : But when I met her, there she was with a packet of cigarettes.\nS6: poor girl!.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSRQ', 'SPQR', 'QPRS', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: When a satellite is launched, the rocket begins by going slowly upwards through the air.\nP : However, the higher it goes, the less air it meets.\nQ : As the rocket goes higher, it travels faster.\nR : For the atmosphere becomes thinner.\nS : As a result there is less friction.\nS6: Consequently, the rocket still does not become too hot.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'QSPR', 'PQRS', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "S1: A father having offered to take the baby out in a perambulator, was tempted by the sunny morning to slip into a pub for a glass of beer.\nP : Indignant at her husband's behaviour, she decided to teach him a lesson.\nQ : She wheeled away the pram.\nR : A little later, his wife came by, where to her horror, she discovered her sleeping baby.\nS : Leaving the pram outside, he disappeared inside the bar.\nS6: She waited for him, anticipating the white face and quivering lips which would soon appear with the news that the baby had been stolen.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SRPQ', 'RQPS', 'SPQR', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: The city is almost a slum and stinks most of time.\nP : The slush on the road did not deter them.\nQ : The occasional slips and falls were considered a small price to pay for the trip.\nR : They were excited, fascinated by the sight of fresh snow on the roads.\nS : Even so, it looked beautiful to tourists of various categories.\nS6: But some visitors came away with the unforgettable sight of young labours scantily clad.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQPS', 'QPRS', 'RSQP', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Venice is a strange and beautiful city in the north of Italy.\nP : There are about four hundred old stone bridges joining the island of Venice.\nQ : In this city there are no motor cars, no horses, no buses.\nR : These small islands are near one another.\nS : It is not an island but a hundred and seventeen islands.\nS6: This is because Venice has no streets.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'PRQS', 'SRPQ', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: The Hound of Baskervilles was feared by the people of the area.\nP : Some people spoke of seeing a huge, shadowy form a Hound at midnight on the moor.\nQ : But they spoke of it in tones of horror.\nR : Nobody had actually seen the hound.\nS : This shadowy form did not reveal any details about the animal.\nS6: The Hound of Baskervilles remains an unsolved mystery.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPQR', 'SPRQ', 'PSRQ', 'PQRS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: A gentleman who lived alone always had two plates placed on the table at dinner time.\nP : One day just as he sat down to dine, the cat rushed in to the room.\nQ : One plate was for himself and other was for his cat.\nR : she drooped a mouse into her own plate and another into her master plate.\nS : He used to give the cat a piece of meat from his own plate.\nS6: In this way the cat showed her gratitude to her master.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QSPR', 'PSRQ', 'QRSP', 'RPQS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: Ants eat worms, centipedes and spiders.\nP : They are usually much quicker than the ant itself.\nQ : Nevertheless, these animals do not make easy game for ants.\nR : Besides, they have an extraordinary number of ways of escaping.\nS : They also eat larvae and insect adults such as flies, moths and spring tails.\nS6: Some jump, and some give out a pungent repellent substance.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'SPRQ', 'SQRP', 'SRQP'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "S1: Satyajit Ray made several films for children.\nP : Later film makers have followed his lead.\nQ : Today other nations are making the children's film in a big way.\nR : This was at a time when no director considered children as potential audience.\nS : Ray was, thus, a pioneer in the field.\nS6: But today few think of Ray as a maker of children's films.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['PSRQ', 'RSQP', 'RSPQ', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Hungary, with a population of about 10 million, lies between Czechoslovakia to the north and Yugoslavia to the south.\nP : Here a great deal of grain is grown.\nQ : In recent years, however, progress has been made also in the field of industrialisation.\nR : Most of this country consists of an extremely fertile plain, through which the river Danube flows.\nS : In addition to grain, the plain produces potatoes, sugar, wine and livestock.\nS6: The new industries derive mainly from agricultural production.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'RPSQ', 'PRSQ', 'RQSP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Palaeobotany is the study of fossil plants preserved in rocks dating back in millions of years.\nP : Records of the history of the world are contained in fossils.\nQ : Through the ages, plants have evolved from simple to more complex forms.\nR : First there were water plants then land plants appeared during the Paleozoic era.\nS : But since the fossil remains appear locked in rock layers, they are closely related to the geologist area of investigation.\nS6: The fossil plants indicate the age of the rock, and also point to facts regarding climate, temperature and topography.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQSP', 'SQRP', 'PSQR', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: On vacation in Tangier, Morocco, my friend and I sat down at a street cafe.\nP : At one point, he bent over with a big smile, showing me, a single gold tooth and a dingy fez.\nQ : soon I felt the presence of someone standing alongside me.\nR : But this one wouldn\'t budge.\nS : We had been cautioned about beggars and were told to ignore them.\nS6: Finally a man walked over to me and whispered, "Hey buddy this guy is your waiter and he wants your order"\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQRP', 'SQPR', 'QSRP', 'QSPR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "S1: And then Gandhi came.\nP : Get off the backs of these peasants and workers, he told us, all you who live by their exploitation.\nQ : He was like a powerful current of fresh air, like a beam of light, like a whirlwind that upset many things.\nR : He spoke their language and constantly dre their attention to their appalling conditions.\nS : He didn't descent from the top, he seemed to emerge from the masses of India.\nS6: Political freedom took new shape and then acquired a new content.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['QSRP', 'SRQP', 'RSQP', 'PRSQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Biological evolution has not fitted man to any specific environment.\nP : It is by no means a biological evolution, but it is a cultural one.\nQ : His imagination, his reason, his emotional subtlety and toughness, makes it possible for him not to accept the environment but to change.\nR : And that series of inventions by which man from age by age has reshaped his environment is a different kind of evolution.\nS : Among the multitude of animals which scamper, burrow swim around us he is in the only one who is not locked in to his environment.\nS6: That brilliant sequence of cultural peaks can most appropriately be termed the ascent of man.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'SRQP', 'QRSP', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: The dictionary is the best friend of you task.\nP : That may not be possible always.\nQ : It is wise to look it up immediately.\nR : Then it must be firmly written on the memory and traced at the first opportunity.\nS : Never allow a strange word to pass unchallenged.\nS6: soon you will realize that this is an exciting task.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'SPQR', 'QRPS', 'SQPR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: The Bhagavadgita recognises the nature of man and the needs of man.\nP : All these three aspects constitute the nature of man.\nQ : It shows how the human being is rational one, an ethical one and a spiritual one.\nR : More than all, it must be a spiritual experience.\nS : Nothing can give him fulfilment unless it satisfies his reason, his ethical conscience.\nS6: A man whom does not harmonise them, is not truly human.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSRQ', 'RSPQ', 'QPSR', 'PSQR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: I usually sleep quite well in the train, but this time I slept only a little.\nP : Most people wanted it shut and I wanted it open.\nQ : As usual, I got angry about the window.\nR : The quarrel left me completely upset.\nS : There were too many people too much huge luggage all around.\nS6: It was shut all night, as usual\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RSQP', 'SQPR', 'SQRP', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: In 1934, William Golding published a small volume of poems.\nP : During the World War II(1939-45) he joined the Royal Navy and was present at the sinking of the Bismarck.\nQ : He returned to teaching in 1945 and gave it up in 1962, and is now a full time writer.\nR : In 1939, he married and started teaching at Vishop Wordsworth school in Salisbury.\nS : At first his novels were not accepted.\nS6: But the Lord of the files which came out in 1954 was welcomed as "a most absorbing and instructive tale".\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'RPSQ', 'SRPQ', 'SQPR'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: The future beckons to us.\nP : In fact we have hard work ahead.\nQ : Where do we go and what shall be our endeavour?\nR : We shall also have to fight and end poverty, ignorance and disease.\nS : It will be to bring freedom and oppurtunity to the common man.\nS6: There is no resting for any one of us till we redeem our pledge in full.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSRQ', 'QPSR', 'QSRP', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Most of the universities in the country are now facing financial crisis.\nP : Cost benefit yardstick thus should not be applied in the case of universities.\nQ : The current state of affairs cannot be allowed to continue for long.\nR : Universities cannot be equated with commercial enterprises.\nS : Proper development of universities and colleges must be ensured.\nS6: The Government should realise this before it is too late.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'QSPR', 'QRSP', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: While talking to a group, one should feel self-confident and courageous.\nP : Nor is it a gift bestowed by providence on only a few.\nQ : One should also learn how to think calmly and clearly.\nR : It is like the ability to play golf.\nS : It is not as difficult as most men imagine.\nS6: Any man can develop his capacity if he has the desire to do so.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'QSPR', 'QRSP', 'RSQP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: A ceiling on urban property.\nP : No mill-owner could own factories or mills or plants.\nQ : And mass circulation papers\nR : Would mean that\nS : No press magnate could own printing presses.\nS6: since their value would exceed the ceiling fixed by the government.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QSRP', 'RPSQ', 'SRPQ', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "S1: The art of growing old is one which the passage of time has forced upon my attention.\nP : One of these is undue absorption in the past.\nQ : One's thought must be directed to the future and to things about which there is something to be done.\nR : Psychologically, there are two dangers to be guarded against in old age.\nS : It does not do to live in memories, in regrets for the good old days, or in sadness about friend who are dead.\nS6: This is not always easy one's own past is gradually increasing weight.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['QSRP', 'RPQS', 'RPSQ', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: I keep on flapping my big ears all day.\nP : They also fear that I will flip them all away.\nQ : But children wonder why I flap them so.\nR : I flap them so to make sure they are safely there on either side of my head.\nS : But I know what I am doing.\nS6: Am I not a smart, intelligent elephant?\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'QPSR', 'QPRS', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': "S1: Once King Shantnu met a young and beautiful fisher girl.\nP : He went to the fisherman and asked him for her asked him for her hand in marriage.\nQ : The King was extremely sad and returned to his palace.\nR : He fell in love with the fisher girl.\nS : The fisherman agreed to it condition that the son of his daughter should be heir to the throne of Hastinapur.\nS6: Devavrata, the King's son, asked him the reason of his sadness.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['PQRS', 'RPSQ', 'QSPR', 'PSQR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Reliogion is not a matter of mere dogmatic conformity.\nP : It is not merely going through the ritual prescribed to us.\nQ : It is not a question of ceremonial piety.\nR : Unless that kind of transformation occurs, you are not an authentically religious man.\nS : It is the remarking of your own self, the transformation of your nature.\nS6: A man of that character is free from fear, free from hatred.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPRQ', 'QPSR', 'PSRQ', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: We speak today of self-determination in politics.\nP : So long as one is conscious of a restraint, it is possible to resist it or to near it as a necessary evil and to keep free in spirit.\nQ : Slavery begins when one ceases to feel that restraint and it depends on if the evil is accepted as good.\nR : There is, however, a subtler domination exercised in the sphere of ideas by one culture to another.\nS : Political subjection primarily means restraint on the outer life of people.\nS6: Cultural subjection is ordinarily of an unconscious character and it implies slavery from the very start.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPRQ', 'RSQP', 'SPQR', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: Once upon a time an ant lived on the bank of river.\nP : The dove saw the ant struggling in water in a helpless condition.\nQ : All its efforts to come up is failed.\nR : One day it suddenly slipped in to water.\nS : A dove lived in the tree on the bank not far from the spot.\nS6: She was touched.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQSP', 'QRPS', 'SRPQ', 'PQRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: The December dance and music season in Madras is like the annual tropical cyclone.\nP : A few among the new aspirants dazzle witht he colour of youth, like fresh saplings.\nQ : It rains an abundance of music for over a fortnight.\nR : Thick clouds expectation charge the atmosphere with voluminous advertisements.\nS : At the end of it one is left with the feeling that the music of only those artists seasoned by careful nurturing, stands tall like well-routed trees.\nS6: Many a hastily planed shrub gets washed away in the storm.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RQPS', 'QRPS', 'RQSP', 'QRSP'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: There is a touching story of Professor Hardy visiting Ramanujan as he lay desperately ill in hospital at Putney.\nP : \'No Hardy, that is not a dull number in the very least.\nQ : Hardy, who was a very shy man, could not find the words for his distress.\nR : It was 1729.\nS : The best he could do, as he got to the beside was "I say Ramanujan, I thought the number of taxi I came down in was a very dull number"\nS6: It is the lowest number that can be expressed in two different ways as the sum of two cubes.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRSQ', 'QSRP', 'QSPR', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Politeness is not a quality possessed by only one nation or race.\nP : One may observe that a man of one nation will remove his hat or fold his hands by way of greetings when he meets someone he knows.\nQ : A man of another country will not to do so.\nR : It is a quality to be found among all peoples and nations in every corner of the earth.\nS : Obviously, each person follows the custom of his particular country.\nS6: In any case, we should not mock at others habits.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'RPSQ', 'PRQS', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Throughout history man has used energy from the sun.\nP : Today, when we burn wood or use electric current we are drawing an energy.\nQ : However we now have a new supply of energy.\nR : All our ordinary life depends on sun.\nS : This has come from the sun.\nS6: This energy comes from inside atoms.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'RQPS', 'QSRP', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: This weather-vane often tops a church spire, tower or high building.\nP : They are only wind-vanes.\nQ : Neither alone can tell us what the weather will be.\nR : They are designed to point to direction from which the wind is coming.\nS : Just as the barometer only tells us the pressure of air, the weather-vane tells us the direction of wind.\nS6: The weather-vane can, however give us some indication of other.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'PSRQ', 'PRSQ', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: But how does a new word get into the dictionary?\nP : When a new dictionary is being edited, a lexicographer collects all the alphabetically arranged citation slips for a particular word.\nQ : The dictionary makers notice it and make a note of it on a citation slip.\nR : The moment new word is coined, it usually enter the spoken language.\nS : The word then passes from the realm of hearing to the realm of writing.\nS6: He sorts them according to their grammatical function, and carefully writes a definition.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'PRSQ', 'RQPS', 'RSQP'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Growing up means not only getting larger, but also using our sense and our brain is to become more aware of things around us.\nP : Not only does he have a memory but he is able to think and reason.\nQ : In this, man differs from all other animals.\nR : Before we spray our roadside plants or turn sewage in to our rivers, we should pause to think what the results of our action are likely to do.\nS : This is to say, he is able to plan what he is is going to do in the light of his experience before he does it.\nS6: In other words, we must develop and use our ability to reason, because the destruction or the preservation of the places in which we live depend on us.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'SPQR', 'SPRQ', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "S1: Jawaharlal Nehru was the greatest plan-enthusiast.\nP : Under Nehru's advice, the pre-Independent congress set up National Planning Commission in 1938.\nQ : But he forgot that what could be achieved by force under the communist dictatorship of Russia was not possible under the democratic set up of India.\nR : He took the idea from Russia where Five year plans transformed a very backward country into a top power of the world.\nS : No free government can call for compulsory sacrifice and suffering from the whole people.\nS6: Nehru himself became the chairman of the commission.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['PSQR', 'SRQP', 'QPRS', 'RQSP'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'S1: Duryodhana was a wicked prince.\nP : one day Bhima made Duryodhana fall from a tree from which Duryodhana was stealing fruits.\nQ : He did not like that Pandavas should be loved and respected by the people of Hastinapur\nR : Duryodhana specially hated Bhima.\nS : Among the Pandavas, Bhima was extraordinary strong and powerful\nS6: This enraged Duryodhana so much that he began to think of removing Bhima from his way.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'QPRS', 'QSPR', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: Jawaharlal Nehru was born in Allahabad on 14 Nov 1889.\nP : Nehru meet Mahatma Gandhi in February 1920.\nQ : In 1905 he was sent to London to study at a school called Haroow.\nR : He became the first Prime Minister of Independent India on 15 August 1947.\nS : He married Kamla Kaul in 1915.\nS6: He died on 27 May 1964.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRPS', 'QSPR', 'RPQS', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: It was a dark moonless night.\nP : He turned over the pages, reading passages here and there.\nQ : He heard them on the floor.\nR : The poet took down his books of poems from his shelves.\nS : Some of them contained his earliest writings which he had almost forgotten.\nS6: They all seemed to him to be poor and ordinary mere childish words.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['RPQS', 'RQSP', 'RSPQ', 'RPSQ'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': "S1: I had halted on the road.\nP : As soon as I saw the elephant I knew I should not shoot him.\nQ : It is a serious matter to shoot a working elephant.\nR : I knew that his 'must' was already passing off.\nS : The elephant was standing 8 yards from the road.\nS6: I decided to watch him for a while and then go home.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SPQR', 'PQSR', 'RQPS', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: There is only one monkey we can thoroughly recommend as an indoor pet.\nP : They quickly die from colds and coughs after the first winter fogs.\nQ : It is beautiful and intelligent Capuchin monkey.\nR : The lively little Capuchins, however, may be left for years in an English house without the least danger to their health.\nS : The Marmosets, it is true, are more beautiful than a Capuchins and just as pleasing, but they are too delicate for the English climate\nS6: Finally let me say that no other monkey has a better temper or winning ways.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'QRPS', 'QSPR', 'RPSQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: A man can be physically confined within stone walls.\nP : But his mind and spirit will still be free.\nQ : Thus his freedom of action may be restricted.\nR : His hopes and aspiration still remain with him.\nS : Hence, he will be free spiritually if not physically.\nS6: No tyranny can intimidate a lover of liberty.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'SRQP', 'QPRS', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: Once upon atime there lived three young men in a certain town of Hindustan.\nP : All the people of the neighbourhood were mortally afraid of them.\nQ : They were so powerful that they could catch growing lions and tear them to pieces.\nR : Someone told them that they would become immortal if they killed Death.\nS : The young men believed themselves to be very good friends.\nS6: All of them set out in search of their foe called Death.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'SQPR', 'RSQP', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Metals are today being replaced by polymers in many applications.\nP : Above all, they are cheaper and easier to process making them a viable alternative to metals.\nQ : Polymers are essentially a long chains of hydrocarbon molecules.\nR : Today polymers as strong as metals have been developed.\nS : These have replaced the traditional chromium-plated metallic bumpers in cars.\nS6: Many Indian Institutes of science and Technology run special programmes on polymer science.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'RSQP', 'RQSP', 'QRPS'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': "S1: Since the sixties there has been an increasing interest in neurophysiology, which deals with the neural bases of mental activity and behaviour.\nP : It has format which is very similar to that of Brain and Language, a sister journal.\nQ : Since then, a number of journals devoted entirely to this area of research have appeared.\nR : Before the 1960's when this field was the concern of a small number of investigators, research articles were scattered in various neurological journals.\nS : Brain and cognition is one such journal.\nS6: So far the journal has published the mixture of articles including reports and investigations.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['RQSP', 'QRSP', 'QSPR', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: An elderly lady suddenly became blind.\nP : The doctor called daily and every time he took away some of her furniture he liked.\nQ : At last she was cured and the doctor demanded his fee.\nR : She agreed to pay a large fee to the doctor who would cure her\nS : On being refused, the doctor wanted to know the reason.\nS6: The lady said that she had not been properly cured because she could not see all his furniture.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'RPQS', 'RSPQ', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: What are the causes of our chronic food shortage ?\nP : To find for these growing new millions is desperate task.\nQ : every year, we add more than a crore of persons to our population.\nR : Despite stupendous efforts by our government, the population is growing unabated.\nS : The chief cause is the population explosion.\nS6: This unprecedented growth can drag us to the doors of starvation very soon.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'SQPR', 'QPRS', 'PSQR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: Our ancestors thought that anything which moved itself was alive.\nP : The philosopher Descartes thought that both men and animals were machines.\nQ : But a machine such as a motorcar or a steamship moves itself, as soon as machines which moved themselves had been made, people asked "Is man a machine?"\nR : And before the days of machinery that was a good definition.\nS : He also thought that the human machine was partly controlled by the soul action on a certain part of the brain, while animals had no souls.\nS6: Therefore some scientists think that life is just a very complicated mechanism.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRSQ', 'RPQS', 'PSQR', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: Payment for imports and exports is made through a system called foreign exchange.\nP : The value of the money of one country in relation to the money of other countries is agreed upon.\nQ : These rates of exchange vary from time to time.\nR : For instance, an American dollar or a British pound sterling is worth certain amounts in the money of other countries.\nS : Sometimes a United States dollar is worth 12 pesos in Mexico.\nS6: Another time it may be worth eight pesos.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'QPRS', 'PRQS', 'RPQS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Moncure Conway devoted his life to two great objects freedom of thought, and freedom of the individual.\nP : They threaten both kinds of freedom.\nQ : But something also has been lost.\nR : There are now dangers, somewhat different in form from those of the past ages.\nS : In regard to both these objects, something has been gained since his time.\nS6: Unless a vigorous and vigilant public opinion can be aroused in defence of them, there will be much less of both a hundred years hence then there is now.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQRS', 'QSPR', 'SQRP', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: The study of speech disorders due to brain injury suggests that patients can think without having adequate control over their language.\nP : But they succeed in playing games of chess.\nQ : Some patients, for example fail to find the names of objects presented to them.\nR : They can even use the concepts needed for chess playing, though they are unable to express many of the concepts in ordinary language.\nS : They even find it difficult to interpret long written notices.\nS6: How they manage to do this we do not know.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'RPSQ', 'QSPR', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: A black haired, young woman came tripping along.\nP : She was leading a young woman wearing a hat.\nQ : The woman swept it off and tossed it in the air.\nR : The child jumped up to catch the hat.\nS : The young man tossed his head to shake the hat back.\nS6: Both disappeared from view.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'RPSQ', 'QRPS', 'SQRP'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: We now know that the oceans are very deep.\nP : For example, the Indian ocean has a range called the Indian Ridge.\nQ : Much of it is fairly flat.\nR : However, there are great mountain ranges as well.\nS : On average the bottom is 2.5 miles to 3.5 miles down\nS6: This reaches from the India to the Antarctic.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'PQSR', 'RSQP', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "S1: Minnie went shopping one morning.\nP : Disappointed She turned around and returned to the parking lot.\nQ : She got out and walked to the nearest shop.\nR : She drove her car into the parking lot and stopped.\nS : It was there that she realised that she'd forgotten her purse at home.\nS6: She drove home with an empty basket.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['RSQP', 'RQSP', 'PQRS', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Far away in a little street there is a poor house.\nP : Her face is thin and worn and her hands are coarse, pricked by a needle, for she is a seam stress.\nQ : One of the windows is open and through it I can see a poor woman.\nR : He has a fever and asking for oranges.\nS : In a bed in a corner of the room her little boy is lying ill.\nS6: His mother has nothing to give but water, so he is crying.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'PQSR', 'QPSR', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: A noise started above their heads.\nP : But people did not take it seriously.\nQ : That was to show everyone that there was something wrong\nR : It was a dangerous thing to do.\nS : For, within minutes the ship began to sink.\nS6: Nearly 200 lives were lost on the fateful day.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQSR', 'PRQS', 'QPRS', 'QPSR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: American private lies may seem shallow.\nP : Students would walk away with books they had not paid for.\nQ : A Chinese journalist commented on a curious institution: the library\nR : Their public morality, however, impressed visitors.\nS : But in general they returned them.\nS6: This would not happen in china, he said.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'QPSR', 'RQPS', 'RPSQ'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: The path of Venus lies inside the path of the Earth.\nP : When at its farthest from the Earth, Venus is 160 million away\nQ : With such a wide range between its greatest and leat distances it is natural that at sometimes Venus appears much brighter than at others.\nR : No other body ever comes so near the Earth, with the exception of the Moon and occasional comet or asteroid.\nS : When Venus is at its nearest to the earth it is only 26 million miles away.\nS6: When at its brightest, it is easily seen with the naked eye in broad daylight.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRPQ', 'SQRP', 'PSQR', 'QPRS'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: In India marriages are usually arranged by parents\nP : Sometimes boys and girls do not like th idea of arranged marriages.\nQ : Most young people accepts the state of affairs.\nR : Shanta was like that.\nS : They assume their parents can make good choices.\nS6: She felt she was a modern girl and not subject for bargaining.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SPRQ', 'PSRQ', 'QSPR', 'RQPS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: She said on the phone that she would report for duty next day.\nP : We waited for few days then we decided to go to her place.\nQ : But she did not.\nR : we found it locked.\nS : Even after that we waited for her quite a few days.\nS6: Eventually we reported to the police.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRSQ', 'QPSR', 'QPRS', 'SQPR'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: Several sub-cities have been planned around capital.\nP : Dwarga is the first among them.\nQ : They are expected to alleviate the problem of housing.\nR : It is coming up in the south west of capital.\nS : It will cater to over one million people when completed.\nS6: Hopefully the housing problem will not be as acute at present after these sub-cities are built.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QPRS', 'PRSQ', 'PQRS', 'QRSP'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: Forecasting the weather has always been a difficult business.\nP : During a period of drought, streams and rivers dried up, the cattle died from thirst and were ruined.\nQ : Many different things affect the weather and we have to study them carefully to make accurate forecast.\nR : Ancient Egyptians had no need of weather in the Nile Valley hardly ever changes.\nS : In early times, when there were no instruments, such as thermometer or the barometer, man looked for tell-tale signs in the sky.\nS6: He made his forecasts by watching flights of the birds or the way smoke rose from fire.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PRQS', 'QPRS', 'QRPS', 'SPQR'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: As he passed beneath her he heard the swish of her wings.\nP : He was not falling head long now.\nQ : The monstrous terror seized him.\nR : But it only lasted a minute.\nS : He could hear nothing.\nS6: The next moment he felt his wings spread outwards.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'QSPR', 'QSRP', 'PRQS'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'S1: Ms. Parasuram started a Petrol Pump in Madras.\nP : A total to 12 girls now work at the pump.\nQ : She advertised in newspapers for women staff.\nR : They operate in 2 shifts.\nS : The response was good.\nS6: Thus she has shown the way for many others.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PQSR', 'SQPR', 'QSPR', 'PQRS'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: Sun birds are among the smallest of Indian birds.\nP : Though they are functionally similar to the humming birds of the New World, they are totally unrelated.\nQ : They do eat insects too.\nR : They are also some of the most brilliantly coloured birds.\nS : sun birds feed on nectar mostly and helped in pollination.\nS6: Our common sun birds are the purple sun bird, the glossy black species and purple rumped sun bird, the yellow and maroon species.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SQPR', 'RPSQ', 'QPRS', 'PSRQ'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: For decades, American society has been calling a melting pot\nP : Differences remained - in appearence, mannerisms, customs, speech, religion and more.\nQ : The term has long been a cliche and half-truth.\nR : But homogenisation was never acheived.\nS : Yes, immigrants from diverse cultures and traditions did cast off vestiges of their native lands and become almost imperceptibly woven in to the American fabric.\nS6: In recent years, such differences accentuated by the arrival of immigrants from Asia and other parts of the world in the United States - have become something to celebrate and to nurture.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QRSP', 'SQRP', 'SQPR', 'QSRP'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'S1: I took cigarettes from my case.\nP : But when the fit of coughing was over, he replaced it between his lips.\nQ : I lit one of them and placed it between the lips.\nR : Then with a feeble hand he removed the cigarette.\nS : Slowly he took a pull at it and coughed violently.\nS6: Then he continues to draw on it.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['PSQR', 'QPSR', 'QSRP', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "S1: There is difference between Gandhiji's concept of secularism and that of Nehru's.\nP : Nehru's idea of secularism was equal indifference to all religions and bothering about none of them.\nQ : According to Gandhiji, all religions are equally true and each scripture is worthy of respect.\nR : Such secularism which means the rejection of all religions is contrary to our culture and tradition.\nS : In Gandhiji's view, secularism stands for equal respect for all religions.\nS6: Instead of doing any good, such secularism can do harm instead of good.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['SQPR', 'PSQR', 'QSPR', 'PRSQ'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: As a dramatist Rabindranath was not what might be called a success.\nP : His dramas were moulded on the lines of the traditional Indian village dramas than the dramas of modern world.\nQ : His plays were more a catalogue of ideas than a vehicle of the expression of action.\nR : Actually the drama has always been the life of Indian people, as it deals with legends of gods and goddesses.\nS : Although in his short stories and novels he was able to create living and well defined characters, he did not seem to be able to do so in dramas\nS6: Therefor, drama forms the essential part of the traditional Indian Culture.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'QPSR', 'QSPR', 'RSQP'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions below, each passage consist of six sentences. The first and sixth sentence are given in the begining. The middle four sentences in each have been removed and jumbled up. These are labelled as P, Q, R and S. Find out the proper order for the four sentences.
[{'question': 'S1: It is regrettable that there is widespread corruption in the country at all levels.\nP : So there is hardly anything that the government can do about it now.\nQ : And there are graft and other malpractices too.\nR : The impression that corruption is universal phenomenon persists and the people not cooperate in checking this evil.\nS : Recently several offenders were brought to book, but they were not given deterrent punishment.\nS6: This is indeed a tragedy of great magnitude.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['QSRP', 'SQRP', 'RSQP', 'PQSR'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'S1: The heart is pump of life.\nP : They have even succeeded in heart transplants.\nQ : Nowadays surgeons are able to stop a patients heart and carry out complicated operations.\nR : A few years ago it was impossible to operate on a patient whose heart was not working properly.\nS : If heart stops we die in about five minutes.\nS6: All this was made possible by the invention of heart-lung machine.\nThe Proper sequence should be:', 'options': ['SRQP', 'SPRQ', 'SQPR', 'SRPQ'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "S1: Your letter was big relief.\nP : How did you exams go?\nQ : After your result, you must come here for a week.\nR : You hadn't written for over a month.\nS : I am sure you will come out with flying colours.\nS6: But don't forget to bring chocolate for Geetha.\nThe Proper sequence should be:", 'options': ['PSRQ', 'QRPS', 'RPSQ', 'RSPQ'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Paragraph Formation
Rearrange the following five sentences in proper sequence so as to for a meaningful paragraph, then answer the questions given below them.
After Examining him, the doctor smiled at him mischievously and took out a syringe.
Thinking that he was really sick, his father summoned the family doctor.
That day, Mintu wanted to take a day off from school
Immediately, Mintu jumped up from his bed and swore the he was fine
Therefor; he pretended to be sick and remained in bed.
[{'question': 'Which sentence should come third in the paragraph?', 'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4', '5'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Which sentence should come last in the paragraph?', 'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4', '5'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Which sentence should come fourth in the paragraph?', 'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4', '5'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Which sentence should come second in the paragraph?', 'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4', '5'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'Which sentence should come first in the paragraph?', 'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4', '5'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Closet Test
Today most businessmen are very worried. To begin with, they are not used to competition.In the past they sold whatever ...(1)... produced at whatever prices they chose. But ...(2)... increasing competition, customers began to ...(3)... and choose. Imports suddenly became ...(4)... available and that too at cheaper ...(5)...
[{'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['it', 'he', 'they', 'we'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['with', 'by', 'after', 'from'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['buy', 'take', 'pick', 'want'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['hardly', 'easily', 'frequently', 'conveniently'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': '(solve as per the direction given above)', 'options': ['costs', 'returns', 'dividend', 'prices'], 'answer': 'd'}]

Comprehension
I felt the wall of the tunnel shiver. The master alarm squealed through my earphones. Almost simultaneously, Jack yelled down to me that there was a warning light on. Fleeting but spectacular sights snapped into ans out of view, the snow, the shower of debris, the moon, looming close and big, the dazzling sunshine for once unfiltered by layers of air. The last twelve hours before re-entry were particular bone-chilling. During this period, I had to go up in to command module. Even after the fiery re-entry splashing down in 81o water in south pacific, we could still see our frosty breath inside the command module.
[{'question': "The word 'Command Module' used twice in the given passage indicates perhaps that it deals with", 'options': ['an alarming journey', 'a commanding situation', 'a journey into outer space', 'a frightful battle.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Which one of the following reasons would one consider as more as possible for the warning lights to be on?', 'options': ['There was a shower of debris.', 'Jack was yelling.', 'A catastrophe was imminent.', 'The moon was looming close and big.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'The statement that the dazzling sunshine was "for once unfiltered by layers of air" means', 'options': ['that the sun was very hot', 'that there was no strong wind', 'that the air was unpolluted', 'none of above'], 'answer': 'd'}]

One Word Substitutes
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Extreme old age when a man behaves like a fool', 'options': ['Imbecility', 'Senility', 'Dotage', 'Superannuation'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'That which cannot be corrected', 'options': ['Unintelligible', 'Indelible', 'Illegible', 'Incorrigible'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The study of ancient societies', 'options': ['Anthropology', 'Archaeology', 'History', 'Ethnology'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A person of good understanding knowledge and reasoning power', 'options': ['Expert', 'Intellectual', 'Snob', 'Literate'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A person who insists on something', 'options': ['Disciplinarian', 'Stickler', 'Instantaneous', 'Boaster'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'State in which the few govern the many', 'options': ['Monarchy', 'Oligarchy', 'Plutocracy', 'Autocracy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A style in which a writer makes a display of his knowledge', 'options': ['Pedantic', 'Verbose', 'Pompous', 'Ornate'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'List of the business or subjects to be considered at a meeting', 'options': ['Schedule', 'Timetable', 'Agenda', 'Plan'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Leave or remove from a place considered dangerous', 'options': ['Evade', 'Evacuate', 'Avoid', 'Exterminate'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A prima facie case is such', 'options': ['As it seems at first sight', 'As it is made to seem at first sight', 'As it turns out to be at the end', 'As it seems to the court after a number of hearings'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A person pretending to be somebody he is not', 'options': ['Magician', 'Rogue', 'Liar', 'Imposter'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A person who knows many foreign languages', 'options': ['Linguist', 'Grammarian', 'Polyglot', 'Bilingual'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'One who has little faith in human sincerity and goodness', 'options': ['Egoist', 'Fatalist', 'Stoic', 'Cynic'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'One who possesses many talents', 'options': ['Versatile', 'Nubile', 'Exceptional', 'Gifted'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Words inscribed on tomb', 'options': ['Epitome', 'Epistle', 'Epilogue', 'Epitaph'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'One who eats everything', 'options': ['Omnivorous', 'Omniscient', 'Irrestible', 'Insolvent'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Malafide case is one', 'options': ['Which is undertaken in a good faith', 'Which is undertaken in a bad faith', 'Which is undertaken after a long delay', 'Which is not undertaken at all'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The custom or practice of having more than one husband at same time', 'options': ['Polygyny', 'Polyphony', 'Polyandry', 'Polychromy'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Tending to move away from the centre or axis', 'options': ['Centrifugal', 'Centripetal', 'Axiomatic', 'Awry'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Teetotaller means', 'options': ['One who abstains from theft', 'One who abstains from meat', 'One who abstains from taking wine', 'One who abstains from malice'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A person interested in collecting, studying and selling of old things', 'options': ['Antiquarian', 'Junk-dealer', 'Crank', 'Archealogist'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A drawing on transparent paper', 'options': ['Red print', 'Blue print', 'Negative', 'Transparency'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'One who is not easily pleased by anything', 'options': ['Maiden', 'Mediaeval', 'Precarious', 'Fastidious'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A remedy for all diseases', 'options': ['Stoic', 'Marvel', 'Panacea', 'Recompense'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'One who is fond of fighting', 'options': ['Bellicose', 'Aggressive', 'Belligerent', 'Militant'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A small shop that sells fashionable clothes, cosmetics, etc.', 'options': ['Store', 'Stall', 'Boutique', 'Booth'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'That which cannot be read', 'options': ['Negligible', 'Illegible', 'Ineligible', 'Incorrigible'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'In a state of tension or anxiety or suspense', 'options': ['Off balance', 'Depressed', 'Diffused', 'On tenterhooks'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'That which cannot be seen', 'options': ['Insensible', 'Intangible', 'Invisible', 'Unseen'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'To slap with a flat object', 'options': ['Chop', 'Hew', 'Gnaw', 'Swat'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Habitually silent or talking little', 'options': ['Servile', 'Unequivocal', 'Taciturn', 'Synoptic'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'One who cannot be corrected', 'options': ['Incurable', 'Incorrigible', 'Hardened', 'Invulnerable'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Be the embodiment or perfect example of', 'options': ['Characterise', 'Idol', 'Personify', 'Signify'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A person not sure of the existence of god', 'options': ['Cynic', 'Agnostic', 'Atheist', 'Theist'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A paper written by hand', 'options': ['Handicraft', 'Manuscript', 'Handiwork', 'Thesis'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'The act of violating the sanctity of the church is', 'options': ['Blashphemy', 'Heresy', 'Sacrilege', 'Desecration'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Something that can be heard', 'options': ['Auditory', 'Audio-visual', 'Audible', 'Audition'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A name adopted by an author in his writings', 'options': ['Nickname', 'Pseudonym', 'Nomenclature', 'Title'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Study of birds', 'options': ['Orology', 'Optology', 'Ophthalmology', 'Ornithology'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A place that provides refuge', 'options': ['Asylum', 'Sanatorium', 'Shelter', 'Orphanage'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A child born after death of his father', 'options': ['Posthumous', 'Orphan', 'Bastard', 'Progenitor'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'The absence of law and order', 'options': ['Rebellion', 'Anarchy', 'Mutiny', 'Revolt'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "The raison d'etre of a controversy is", 'options': ['The enthusiasm with which it is kept alive', 'The fitness with which participants handle it', 'The reason or justification of its existence', 'The unending hostility the parties concerned have towards each other'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A place where bees are kept in called', 'options': ['An apiary', 'A mole', 'A hive', 'A sanctury'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A religious discourse', 'options': ['Preach', 'Stanza', 'Sanctorum', 'Sermon'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': "Parts of a country behind the coast or a river's banks", 'options': ['Isthmus', 'Archipelago', 'Hinterland', 'Swamps'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Study of the evolution of man as an animal', 'options': ['Archaeology', 'Anthropology', 'Chronology', 'Ethnology'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A person who speaks many languages', 'options': ['Linguist', 'Monolingual', 'Polyglot', 'Bilingual'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'One who does not believe in existence of god', 'options': ['Egoist', 'Atheist', 'Stoic', 'Naive'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A disease of mind causing an uncontrollable desire to steal', 'options': ['Schizophrenia', 'Claustrophobia', 'Kleptomania', 'Magolomania'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'One who sacrifices his life for a cause', 'options': ['Patriot', 'Martyr', 'Revolutionary', 'Soldier'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A person who brings goods illegally into the country', 'options': ['Importer', 'Exporter', 'Fraud', 'Smuggler'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'To take secretly in small quantities', 'options': ['Robbery', 'Pilferage', 'Theft', 'Defalcation'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To accustom oneself to a foreign climate', 'options': ['Adapt', 'Adopt', 'Accustom', 'Acclimatise'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'One who knows everything', 'options': ['Literate', 'Scholar', 'Omnipotent', 'Omniscient'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Detailed plan of journey', 'options': ['Travelogue', 'Travelkit', 'Schedule', 'Itinerary'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "Giving undue favours to one's own kith and kin", 'options': ['Nepotism', 'Favouritism', 'Wordliness', 'Corruption'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Hater of learning and knowledge', 'options': ['Misologist', 'Bibliophile', 'Misogynist', 'Misanthropist'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A person interested in reading books and nothing else', 'options': ['Book-keepr', 'Scholar', 'Book-worm', 'Student'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A place where monks live as a secluded community', 'options': ['Cathedral', 'Diocese', 'Convent', 'Monastery'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Incapable of being seen through', 'options': ['Ductile', 'Opaque', 'Obsolete', 'Potable'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'One who does not care for literature or art', 'options': ['Primitive', 'Illiterate', 'Philistine', 'Barbarian'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A large sleeping-room with many beds', 'options': ['Bedroom', 'Dormitory', 'Hostel', 'Basement'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Continuing fight between parties, families, clans, etc.', 'options': ['Enmity', 'Feud', 'Quarrel', 'Skirmish'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A building for storing threshed grain', 'options': ['Hangar', 'Dockyard', 'Store', 'Granary'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Policeman riding on motorcycles as guards to a VIP', 'options': ['Outriders', 'Servants', 'Commandos', 'Attendants'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'One who is determined to exact full vengeance for wrongs done to him', 'options': ['Virulent', 'Vindictive', 'Usurer', 'Vindicator'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Murder of a king', 'options': ['Infanticide', 'Matricide', 'Genocide', 'Regicide'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'An expression of mild disapproval', 'options': ['Warning', 'Denigration', 'Impertinence', 'Reproof'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'One absorbed in his own thoughts and feelings rather than in things outside', 'options': ['Scholar', 'Recluse', 'Introvert', 'Intellectual'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'One who dabbles in fine arts for the love of it and not for monetary gains', 'options': ['Connoisseur', 'Amateur', 'Professional', 'Dilettante'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A school boy who cuts classes frequently is a', 'options': ['Defeatist', 'Sycophant', 'Truant', 'Martinet'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'Ready to believe', 'options': ['Credulous', 'Credible', 'Creditable', 'Incredible'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Medical study of skin and its diseases', 'options': ['Dermatology', 'Endocrinology', 'Gynealogy', 'Orthopaedics'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A person who tries to deceive people by claiming to be able to do wonderful things', 'options': ['Trickster', 'Imposter', 'Magician', 'Mountebank'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A dramatic performance', 'options': ['Mask', 'Mosque', 'Masque', 'Mascot'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'One who does not marry, especially as a religious obligation', 'options': ['Bachelor', 'Celibate', 'Vigin', 'Recluse'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'That which is perceptible by touch is', 'options': ['Contagious', 'Contingent', 'Tenacious', 'Tangible'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Very pleasing to eat', 'options': ['Appetising', 'Palatable', 'Tantalising', 'Sumptuous'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The part of government which is concerned with making of rules', 'options': ['Court', 'Tribunal', 'Bar', 'Legislature'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'One who believes that all things and events in life are predetermined is a', 'options': ['Fatalist', 'Puritan', 'Egoist', 'Tyrant'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Something that relates to everyone in the world', 'options': ['General', 'Common', 'Usual', 'Universal'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'To walk with slow or regular Steps is to', 'options': ['Limp', 'Stride', 'Pace', 'Advance'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'A style full of words', 'options': ['Verbose', 'Pedantic', 'Rhetorical', 'Abundant'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Murder of a brother', 'options': ['Patricide', 'Regicide', 'Homicide', 'Fratricide'], 'answer': 'd'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Having superior or intellectual interests and tastes', 'options': ['Elite', 'Highbrow', 'Sophisticated', 'Fastidious'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To cause troops, etc. to spread out in readiness for battle', 'options': ['Disperse', 'Deploy', 'Collocate', 'Align'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A voice loud enough to be heard', 'options': ['Audible', 'Applaudable', 'Laudable', 'Oral'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'A light sailing boat built specially for racing', 'options': ['Canoe', 'Yacht', 'Frigate', 'Dinghy'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'One who is in charge of museum', 'options': ['Curator', 'Supervisor', 'Caretaker', 'Warden'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'A government by the nobles', 'options': ['Aristocracy', 'Democracy', 'Autocracy', 'Bureaucracy'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'One who is honourably discharged from service', 'options': ['Retired', 'Emeritus', 'Relieved', 'Emancipated'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Present opposing arguments or evidence', 'options': ['Criticise', 'Rebuff', 'Reprimand', 'Rebut'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': "The policy of extending a country's empire and influence", 'options': ['Communism', 'Internationalism', 'Capitalism', 'Imperialism'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Of outstanding significance', 'options': ['Monumental', 'Rational', 'Ominous', 'Evident'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In questions given below out of four alternatives, choose the one which can be substituted for the given word/sentence.
[{'question': 'Code of diplomatic etiquette and precedence', 'options': ['Statesmanship', 'Formalism', 'Hierarchy', 'Protocol'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A fixed orbit in space in relation to earth', 'options': ['Geological', 'Geo-synchronous', 'Geo-centric', 'Geo-stationary'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'That which cannot be believed', 'options': ['Incredible', 'Incredulous', 'Implausible', 'Unreliable'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'To issue a thunderous verbal attack', 'options': ['Languish', 'Animate', 'Fulminate', 'Invigorate'], 'answer': 'c'}]

Idioms and Phrases
Some proverbs/idioms are given below together with their meanings. Choose the correct meaning of proverb/idiom, If there is no correct meaning given, E (i.e.) 'None of these' will be the answer.
[{'question': 'To make clean breast of', 'options': ['To gain prominence', 'To praise oneself', 'To confess without of reserve', 'To destroy before it blooms', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': "To keeps one's temper", 'options': ['To become hungry', 'To be in good mood', 'To preserve ones energy', 'To be aloof from', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To catch a tartar', 'options': ['To trap wanted criminal with great difficulty', 'To catch a dangerous person', 'To meet with disaster', "To deal with a person who is more than one's match", 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To drive home', 'options': ["To find one's roots", 'To return to place of rest', 'Back to original position', 'To emphasise', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'To have an axe to grind', 'options': ['A private end to serve', 'To fail to arouse interest', 'To have no result', 'To work for both sides', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Some proverbs/idioms are given below together with their meanings. Choose the correct meaning of proverb/idiom, If there is no correct meaning given, E (i.e.) 'None of these' will be the answer.
[{'question': 'To cry wolf', 'options': ['To listen eagerly', 'To give false alarm', 'To turn pale', 'To keep off starvation', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To end in smoke', 'options': ['To make completely understand', 'To ruin oneself', 'To excite great applause', 'To overcome someone', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To be above board', 'options': ['To have a good height', 'To be honest in any business deal', 'They have no debts', 'To try to be beautiful', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': "To put one's hand to plough", 'options': ['To take up agricultural farming', 'To take a difficult task', 'To get entangled into unnecessary things', 'Take interest in technical work', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'To pick holes', 'options': ['To find some reason to quarrel', 'To destroy something', 'To criticise someone', 'To cut some part of an item', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'c'}]
Some proverbs/idioms are given below together with their meanings. Choose the correct meaning of proverb/idiom, If there is no correct meaning given, E (i.e.) 'None of these' will be the answer.
[{'question': 'To leave someone in the lurch', 'options': ['To come to compromise with someone', 'Constant source of annoyance to someone', 'To put someone at ease', 'To desert someone in his difficulties', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'To play second fiddle', 'options': ['To be happy, cheerful and healthy', "To reduce importance of one's senior", 'To support the role and view of another person', 'To do back seat driving', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'To beg the question', 'options': ['To refer to', 'To take for granted', 'To raise objections', 'To be discussed', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'A black sheep', 'options': ['An unlucky person', 'A lucky person', 'An ugly person', 'A partner who takes no share of the profits', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'e'}, {'question': 'A man of straw', 'options': ['A man of no substance', 'A very active person', 'A worthy fellow', 'An unreasonable person', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Some proverbs/idioms are given below together with their meanings. Choose the correct meaning of proverb/idiom, If there is no correct meaning given, E (i.e.) 'None of these' will be the answer.
[{'question': 'To smell a rat', 'options': ['To see signs of plague epidemic', 'To get bad small of a bad dead rat', 'To suspect foul dealings', 'To be in a bad mood', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'To hit the nail right on the head', 'options': ['To do the right thing', "To destroy one's reputation", "To announce one's fixed views", 'To teach someone a lesson', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': "To set one's face against", 'options': ['To oppose with determination', 'To judge by appearence', 'To get out of difficulty', 'To look at one steadily', 'None of these'], 'answer': 'a'}]

Change of Voice
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Active/Passive voice. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Passive/Active voice.
[{'question': 'After driving professor Kumar to the museum she dropped him at his hotel.', 'options': ['After being driven to the museum, Professor Kumar was dropped at his hotel.', 'Professor Kumar was being driven dropped at his hotel.', 'After she had driven Professor Kumar to the museum she had dropped him at his hotel.', 'After she was driven Professor Kumar to the museum she had dropped him at his hotel.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I remember my sister taking me to the museum.', 'options': ['I remember I was taken to the museum by my sister.', 'I remember being taken to the museum by my sister.', 'I remember myself being taken to the museum by my sister.', 'I remember taken to the museum by my sister.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Who is creating this mess?', 'options': ['Who has been created this mess?', 'By whom has this mess been created?', 'By whom this mess is being created?', 'By whom is this mess being created?'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'They greet me cheerfully every morning.', 'options': ['Every morning I was greeted cheerfully.', 'I am greeted cheerfully by them every morning.', 'I am being greeted cheerfully by them every morning.', 'Cheerful greeting is done by them every morning to me.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Darjeeling grows tea.', 'options': ['Tea is being grown in Darjeeling.', 'Let the tea be grown in Darjeeling.', 'Tea is grown in Darjeeling.', 'Tea grows in Darjeeling.'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Active/Passive voice. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Passive/Active voice.
[{'question': 'They have built a perfect dam across the river.', 'options': ['Across the river a perfect dam was built.', 'A perfect dam has been built by them across the river.', 'A perfect dam should have been built by them.', 'Across the river was a perfect dam.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'Do you imitate others?', 'options': ['Are others being imitated by you?', 'Are others imitated by you?', 'Have others being imitated by you?', 'Were others being imitated by you?'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'You need to clean your shoes properly.', 'options': ['Your shoes are needed to clean properly.', 'You are needed to clean your shoes properly.', 'Your shoes need to be cleaned properly.', 'Your shoes are needed by you to clean properly.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'He is said to be very rich.', 'options': ['He said he is very rich.', 'People say he is very rich.', 'He said it is very rich.', 'People say it is very rich.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The invigilator was reading out the instructions.', 'options': ['The instructions were read by the invigilator.', 'The instructions were being read out by the invigilator.', 'The instructions had been read out by the invigilator.', 'The instructions had been read by the invigilator.'], 'answer': 'b'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Active/Passive voice. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Passive/Active voice.
[{'question': 'You can play with these kittens quite safely.', 'options': ['These kittens can played with quite safely.', 'These kittens can play with you quite safely.', 'These kittens can be played with you quite safely.', 'These kittens can be played with quite safely.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'A child could not have done this mischief.', 'options': ['This mischief could not be done by a child.', 'This mischief could not been done by a child.', 'This mischief could not have been done by a child.', 'This mischief a child could not have been done.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'James Watt discovered the energy of steam.', 'options': ['The energy of steam discovered James Watt.', 'The energy of steam was discovered by James Watt.', 'James Watt was discovered by the energy of steam.', 'James Watt had discovered energy by the steam.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'She makes cakes every Sunday.', 'options': ['Every Sunday cakes made by her.', 'Cakes are made by her every Sunday.', 'Cakes make her every Sunday.', 'Cakes were made by her every Sunday.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'She spoke to the official on duty.', 'options': ['The official on duty was spoken to by her', 'The official was spoken to by her on duty.', 'She was spoken to by the official on duty.', 'She was the official to be spoken to on duty.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Active/Passive voice. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Passive/Active voice.
[{'question': 'The doctor advised the patient not to eat rice.', 'options': ['The patient was advised by the doctor not to eat rice.', 'The patient was advised by the doctor that he should not eat rice.', 'The patient was being advised by the doctor that he should not rice by the doctor.', 'The patient has been advised not to eat rice by the doctor.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'I cannot accept your offer.', 'options': ['Your offer cannot be accepted by me.', 'I cannot be accepted by your offer.', 'The offer cannot be accepted by me.', 'Your offer cannot be accepted.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'You should open the wine about three hours before you use it.', 'options': ['Wine should be opened about three hours before use.', 'Wine should be opened by you three hours before use.', 'Wine should be opened about three hours before you use it.', 'Wine should be opened about three hours before it is used.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'They will inform the police.', 'options': ['The police will be informed by them.', 'The police will inform them.', 'The police are informed by them.', 'Informed will be the police by them.'], 'answer': 'a'}]

Change of Speech
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Direct/Indirect speech. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Indirect/Direct speech.
[{'question': '"If you don\'t keep quiet I shall shoot you", he said to her in a calm voice.', 'options': ["He warned her to shoot if she didn't keep quiet calmly.", "He said calmly that I shall shoot you if you don't be quiet.", "He warned her calmly that he would shoot her if she didn't keep quiet.", 'Calmly he warned her that be quiet or else he will have to shoot her.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'I told him that he was not working hard.', 'options': ['I said to him, "You are not working hard."', 'I told to him, "You are not working hard."', 'I said, "You are not working hard."', 'I said to him, "He is not working hard."'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'His father ordered him to go to his room and study.', 'options': ['His father said, "Go to your room and study."', 'His father said to him, "Go and study in your room."', 'His father shouted, "Go right now to your study room"', 'His father said firmly, "Go and study in your room."'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'He said to his father, "Please increase my pocket-money."', 'options': ['He told his father, "Please increase the pocket-money"', 'He pleaded his father to please increase my pocket money.', 'He requested his father to increase his pocket-money.', 'He asked his father to increase his pocket-money.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'She said that her brother was getting married.', 'options': ['She said, "Her brother is getting married."', 'She told, "Her brother is getting married."', 'She said, "My brother is getting married."', 'She said, "My brother was getting married."'], 'answer': 'c'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Direct/Indirect speech. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Indirect/Direct speech.
[{'question': 'The boy said, "Who dare call you a thief?"', 'options': ['The boy enquired who dared call him a thief.', 'The boy asked who called him a thief.', 'The boy told that who dared call him a thief.', 'The boy wondered who dared call a thief.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'She exclaimed with sorrow that was a very miserable plight.', 'options': ['She said with sorrow, "What a pity it is."', 'She said, "What a mystery it is."', 'She said, "What a miserable sight it is."', 'She said, "What a miserable plight it is."'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'Dhruv said that he was sick and tired of working for that company.', 'options': ['Dhruv said, "I am sick and tired of working for this company."', 'Dhruv said, "He was tired of that company."', 'Dhruv said to me, "I am sick and tired of working for this company."', 'Dhruv said, "I will be tired of working for that company."'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': '"Are you alone, my son?" asked a soft voice close behind me.', 'options': ['A soft voice asked that what I was doing there alone.', 'A soft voice said to me are you alone son.', 'A soft voice from my back asked If I was alone.', 'A soft voice behind me asked If I was alone.'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'She said to him, "Why don\'t you go today?"', 'options': ['She asked him why he did not go that day.', "She said to him why he don't go that day.", 'She asked him not to go that day.', 'She asked him why he did not go today.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Direct/Indirect speech. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Indirect/Direct speech.
[{'question': 'He exclaimed with joy that India had won the Sahara Cup.', 'options': ['He said, "India has won the Sahara Cup"', 'He said, "India won the Sahara Cup"', 'He said, "How! India will win the Sahara Cup"', 'He said, "Hurrah! India has won the Sahara Cup"'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'The little girl said to her mother, "Did the sun rise in the East?"', 'options': ['The little girl said to her mother that the sun rose in the East.', 'The little girl asked her mother if the sun rose in the East.', 'The little girl said to her mother if the sun rises in the East.', 'The little girl asked her mother if the sun is in the East.'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'The man said, "No, I refused to confers guilt."', 'options': ['The man emphatically refused to confers guilt.', 'The man refused to confers his guilt.', 'The man told that he did not confers guilt.', 'The man was stubborn enough to confers guilt.'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'Nita ordered her servant to bring her cup of tea.', 'options': ['Nita told her servant, "Bring a cup of tea."', 'Nita said, "Bring me a cup of tea."', 'Nita said to her servant, "Bring me a cup of tea."', 'Nita told her servant, "Bring her that cup of tea."'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'My cousin said, "My room-mate had snored throughout the night."', 'options': ['my cousin said that her room-mate snored throughout the night.', 'my cousin told me that her room-mate snored throughout the night.', 'my cousin complained to me that her room-mate is snoring throughout the night.', 'my cousin felt that her room-mate may be snoring throughout the night.'], 'answer': 'a'}]
In the questions below the sentences have been given in Direct/Indirect speech. From the given alternatives, choose the one which best expresses the given sentence in Indirect/Direct speech.
[{'question': '"Please don\'t go away", she said.', 'options': ['She said to please her and not go away.', 'She told me to go away.', 'She begged me not to go away.', 'She begged that I not go away.'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'She said to her friend, "I know where is everyone"', 'options': ['She told that she knew where was everyone.', 'She told her friend that she knew where was everyone.', 'She told her friend that she knew where is everyone.', 'She told her friend that she knows where was everyone.'], 'answer': 'b'}]

Verbal Analogies
Each question consist of two words which have a certain relationship to each other followed by four pairs of related words, Select the pair which has the same relationship.
[{'question': 'DIVA:OPERA', 'options': ['producer:theatre', 'director:drama', 'conductor:bus', 'thespian:play'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'GRAIN:SALT', 'options': ['shard:pottery', 'shred:wood', 'blades:grass', 'chip:glass'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'THRUST:SPEAR', 'options': ['mangle:iron', 'scabbard:sword', 'bow:arrow', 'fence:epee'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'PAIN:SEDATIVE', 'options': ['comfort:stimulant', 'grief:consolation', 'trance:narcotic', 'ache:extraction'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'LIGHT:BLIND', 'options': ['speech:dumb', 'language:deaf', 'tongue:sound', 'voice:vibration'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Each question consist of two words which have a certain relationship to each other followed by four pairs of related words, Select the pair which has the same relationship.
[{'question': 'WAN:COLOUR', 'options': ['corpulent:weight', 'insipid:flavour', 'pallid:complexion', 'enigmatic:puzzle'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'PORK:PIG', 'options': ['rooster:chicken', 'mutton:sheep', 'steer:beef', 'lobster:crustacean'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'AFTER:BEFORE', 'options': ['first:second', 'present:past', 'contemporary:historic', 'successor:predecessor'], 'answer': 'd'}, {'question': 'INDIGENT:WEALTHY', 'options': ['angry:rich', 'native:affluent', 'gauche:graceful', 'scholarly:erudite'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'DISTANCE:MILE', 'options': ['liquid:litre', 'bushel:corn', 'weight:scale', 'fame:television'], 'answer': 'a'}]
Each question consist of two words which have a certain relationship to each other followed by four pairs of related words, Select the pair which has the same relationship.
[{'question': 'TEN:DECIMAL', 'options': ['seven:septet', 'four:quartet', 'two:binary', 'five:quince'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'MUNDANE:SPIRITUAL', 'options': ['common:ghostly', 'worldly:unworldly', 'routine:novel', 'secular:clerical'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'ARMY:LOGISTICS', 'options': ['business:strategy', 'soldier:students', 'war:logic', 'team:individual'], 'answer': 'a'}, {'question': 'GRAVITY:PULL', 'options': ['iron:metal', 'north pole:directions', 'magnetism:attraction', 'dust:desert'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'FILTER:WATER', 'options': ['curtail:activity', 'expunge:book', 'edit:text', 'censor:play'], 'answer': 'd'}]
Each question consist of two words which have a certain relationship to each other followed by four pairs of related words, Select the pair which has the same relationship.
[{'question': 'HOPE:ASPIRES', 'options': ['love:elevates', 'film:flam', 'fib:lie', 'fake:ordinary'], 'answer': 'c'}, {'question': 'CORPOREAL:SPIRITUAL', 'options': ['mesa:plateau', 'moron:savant', 'foreigner:immigrant', 'pedagogue:teacher'], 'answer': 'b'}, {'question': 'SYMPHONY:COMPOSER', 'options': ['Leonardo:music', 'Fresco:painter', 'colours:pallet', 'art:appreciation'], 'answer': 'b'}]
